对
Yes.
欢迎来到第三周：开源循环时尚。
And welcome to week three, open source, circular Fashion
本次由 Zoe Romano 主讲。
with Zoe Romano.
接下来把发言交给你。
I give you the floor so that you can
好的，谢谢
Okay. Thank
我们，一切
Us. Everything about
是的 谢谢
Yes. Thank you.
欢迎来到这个新班级
And welcome to this new class.
很高兴看到这些新面孔
Happy to, to see all these new faces for the,
这一届 Fabricademy。
this edition of Fabric Academy.
现在我分享我的屏幕。
Now I share my screen.
是的，这个？
Yes. This one?
你能看见吗？
Mm-hmm. Can you see Yes,
是的 如果你有的话
Yes. If you had
视频。您是否有视频在
videos. Did you have videos in
你的介绍？
Your presentation? Yes, but
声音不是，不是必需的，所以，好吧，
the sound is not, is not necessary, so, okay,
不错
Perfect.
呃，让我看看能不能，好吧，你好
Uh, let me see if I can, okay. Hello.
所以我很高兴在这里度过第九年
So I'm glad to be here for the ninth year,
自从这次冒险活动开始
and since the beginning of this, uh, adventure venture,
我觉得自己，呃， 非常舒服，嗯，
I felt myself, uh, very comfortable with, um,
Fabricademy 的方法
the approach of fabric academy
因为我是那种，嗯，奇怪，呃，
because I'm a kind of, um, weird, uh,
假设制造者是因为我的背景是哲学
let's say maker because my background is in philosophy.
但我有一位媒体科技大师
But, uh, I had a master in media science and technology.
但是，我，我主要工作 在开始。
And, but I, I work mainly at the beginning.
我的职业，呃，生活开始
My professional, uh, life started
与工作 在战略传播。
with the working in strategic communication.
而且，呃，我的意思是， 它更多的是数字，呃，
And, uh, I mean, it was more for the digital, uh,
公司数字化
um, digital becoming of companies
从传单转到网站。
moving from the leaflet to the website.
然后我，当我工作的时候，我在做那个工作，
And then I also, while I was working, I was doing that job,
我，我作为一个媒体活动家工作。
I, I worked at as a media activist.
我会告诉你这个方法。
And I will tell you a bit about this approach.
在那之后，我在Arduino队工作了四年
Uh, after that, I worked for Arduino team for four years
并管理来文
and to manage the communication
还有一点社区技术和可穿戴技术
and also a bit of community and wearable technology.
然后在2014年，我共同创立了一个
And then in 2014, I co-founded one
在米拉姆的首个制作空间
of the first maker spaces here in Milam
这尤其侧重于设计和时尚。
that was focused especially on design and fashion.
所以，呃，从2019年开始，呃，我是一个自由职业者，
So, uh, since 2019, uh, I'm a freelancer,
所以我离开了制造空间的管理。
so I left the managing of the makerspace.
而我实际上，我更有能力
And I'm actually in, I'm more able to
重点是项目。
focus on projects.
我更能专注于特定的垂直项目，
I'm more able to focus on specific vertical project,
特别是欧洲联盟委员会的资助。
especially funded by, uh, European Commission.
而且，呃，通常他们，呃，
And, uh, and usually they are, uh,
感人话题，呃， 社会影响，嗯，
touching topics like, uh, social impact, um,
由开源驱动
being driven by, uh, open source
和数字技术，呃，特别是现在，
and digital technologies in, uh, especially right now,
因为当我说这个， 我工作的地方的定义，
because when I say this, the definition where I work,
我说，是的，但你是做什么的？
I say, yes, but what do you do?
举个例子，我现在正在研究这个
Basically, for example, right now I'm working on this, uh,
基于高山空间的木板项目，
woodshed project that is based on the alpine space,
在山上，在意大利北部，
on the mountains, on the Northern Italy
以及欧洲其他四个国家。
and other four countries in Europe.
我们正在研究如何解决这个问题
And we are looking at how to solve the issue
粗毛的羊毛，
of coarse wool.
所以我们在高山地区有很多羊
So we, in the alpine spaces, we have a lot of sheep,
我们有绵羊
and we sheep we have sheep
因为我们，呃，他们是好动物
because we, uh, they are good animals
管理风景，
to manage the landscape,
我们吃羊肉
but also we eat the meat of the, of the sheep
并用他们的牛奶做奶酪。
and make cheese outta their milk.
这艘船的具体特征是
And the specific of this, uh, ship is
他们的羊毛并不像美里诺羊毛那么柔软
that their wool is not really soft as the merino wool
这是最常用的羊毛 在时尚系统，
that is the most used wool in, in the fashion system,
羊毛是更厚的，
but is a wool that is thicker
而且，呃， 粗体更强， 更富有。
and is, uh, coarser is stronger, is more richy.
因此，我们正在寻找方法，去研究并使用它。
And so we are finding way to, to work on it and use it.
否则，它被当成，嗯，
Otherwise, it's been treated as a, as, um,
浪费而不是资源。
waste instead of being a resource.
我们意大利有个传统
We have a tradition in Italy,
学校所在的其他空心空间
but also in the other aine spaces where this school was
一种特殊的珍贵材料
considered a, a special precious material
因为它有很多，嗯， 特征，
because it has a lot of, um, features that,
让他们变得非常，嗯，珍贵
that makes them, makes it a very, um, precious
以不能入火门者发誓，
regarding being able not to get into fire,
可持续 柔软
being sustainable, being, uh, soft
并且可以用来保持热，例如，
and can be used to keep the heat, for example,
房子里有很多很多的特征
inside the houses, so many, many features.
所以，我们想看看，如果， 如何利用
So what we are trying to see if, how in which way we can use
用这个工具制作其他产品。
and make other products out of this tool.
比如，我在这里合作
For example, here, I collaborated
并做了一个小小的研究 案例研究，嗯，如何
and made a little research case study on, uh, how
你知道，射击时的技巧
to tuft, you know, the tufting technology when you shoot
枪，我喜欢的枪， 射击羊毛的枪。
with a gun, the gun that I like, the guns that shoot wool.
然后，嗯，我们在一起
And, um, we attached together
在马德里的本地工作室， 我们把这个，嗯，
with local studio in Madrid, we attached this, um,
把枪给机器人
tufting gun to a robot,
我们开始测试所有的羊毛
and we started to test all the wool
我从意大利带来的
that I brought from Italy
不同种类的船舶
of different type of, of breed of ship.
因此，我们理解 如果我们可以工作 一个概念
And so we are understanding if we can work on a concept
在高山空间的微构物，
of microfactory in the alpine space that can,
嗯，制造羊毛
uh, manufacture the wool
还创造了价值更高的产品。
and also create products at a higher value.
所以这个想法，这个方法是一种
So this idea, this approach is a kind
系统设计方法， 其中你认为一个问题，
of systemic design approach in which you think a problem,
一个问题，一个珍贵的材料
an issue, a material that is precious
以何种方式你可以得到这种材料
and in which way you can have this material
被当地使用，而不是移动 全国各地，
to be used locally and not moving it around in the country,
却能创造更多，
but being there, being able to create a more,
小型供应链
a small supply chain
并使用数字制作，以吸引年轻人参与
and use digital fabrication in order to engage young people
组成初创企业
in making up startups
或能够创建这类公司的小公司，
or small companies that can create these type of,
嗯，产品。
um, products.
还有 呃 呃 在
And, uh, um, in,
在这个圈套里，我也教
in within this cons concept, I also teach
在Theus学院内部， 我，我做了一个课程
in inside the Theus Academy, I, I make a course
这叫做摇篮到摇篮时尚制作。
that is called Cradle to Cradle Fashion Making.
而是如何应用 制作，
And it's about how to apply making,
因此，数字制造技术 在这个想法
so digital fabrication technology within the idea
具有可持续性的时尚制造业，呃，
of fashion manufacturing with a sustainability, uh,
一个可持续性，嗯，方法。
a sustainability, um, approach.
因此，有了产品，
So being able to have products in which,
产品在生命末期会怎样
you know, what happens to the products at the end of life.
嗯，最近我参加了，嗯， 其实去年我参加了
Um, recently I took part, uh, actually last year I took part
参加这个，呃，这个叫会议，
to this, uh, conference that is called,
名为"设计中的常识"，
that was titled Commons in Design,
而实际上在尝试
and actually was trying
来了解我们如何应用设计，嗯，
to understanding which way we can apply design, uh,
在公有制度范围内。
within the framework of the commons.
我，在这本书里，有一篇论文，呃，
And I, in, in this book, there is a, a paper, uh,
就像我写的一章 叫做低技术，
like a chapter that I wrote that is called Low Tech,
这是新高科技。
is the New High Tech.
所以，在哪种方式， 不知何故，我们正在尝试
So in which way, somehow we are trying
将传统的制造系统与
to merge the traditional manufacturing system with
当代制造系统寻找平衡
the, uh, contemporary manufacturing system to find a balance
找到可以设想的解决办法
between the two and find solution that can be conceived
作为数字，呃，分布式制造。
as digital, uh, distributed manufacturing.
在上课期间 我会试着
And during this lesson, I will try to, um,
潜入这个概念，理解
dive you into, into this concept, understanding
这是什么意思，呃，分销商制造，
what does it mean digital, uh, distributor manufacturing,
以何为常识
in which way the commons
开放的概念 真的很重要
and the concept of openness is really important
新的生产框架。
for this new framework of production.
嗯，一个，另一个论文，我写，
Um, one of the, another paper that I wrote,
虽然老了，但还是很有价值的
this is older, but I think is still valuable
有趣的是 这个想法
and interesting, is the, um, idea that
新设计师需要
the new designers are, um, need to
设想和设计易于修理的产品。
conceive and design products that are easily repairable.
而修理的便利 对我们来说，
And the easy of repair is for us,
设计一个DL，意思是
a design a DL in the sense that
修补不该是什么
repairing shouldn't be something
别人想到当一个产品坏了，
that someone else think about when a product is broken,
但它是能够增加
but it's something that can increase the
产品的寿命。
lifespan of products.
所以设计师的首要职责是构思
So first responsibility of designer is to conceive
产品有这种，嗯，轻松
products that have this, um, easy easiness
来修补
of, uh, uh, repairing in.
呃，但我怎么来的？
Uh, but how did I arrive here?
这样我 我 我
In which way I, I, I,
假设说，发现了开放的想法。
let's say, discovered the idea of openness.
嗯，首先，我谈论，
Um, first of all, I talk about,
我说的是开放的想法，嗯，
I talk about in which way the idea of openness, um,
嗯，帮助我们，嗯， 设想一种新的方式，
uh, helped us, uh, conceive a new way of,
想想时尚，特别是米兰
uh, thinking about fashion, especially Milan.
米兰是个充满时尚和设计的城市
Milan is a city, I mean, that is full of fashion and design.
有设计周
There are design weeks
和时尚周，嗯，不止一次 一年，一年。
and fashion weeks, um, more than once time a, a, a year.
我的大部分朋友，嗯，从一开始
And most of my friends, um, at the beginning
这个世纪，真的，呃，
of the century was really, uh,
为这个工作。
working for this.
我的意思是，当你20岁， 当你想要工作
I mean, when you are 20 years old, when you want to work
你正在学习
with, um, uh, you're studying
也许你需要找份工作，你去
and maybe you need to have some kind of job, you go
并工作 像时尚猫行或类似的东西。
and work for like fashion catwalk or things like that.
还有很多事情，你知道
And there is a lot, and you realize
有很多的剥削。
that there is a lot of exploiting.
所以，剥削不只是外面
So the exploiting is not just outside
我们制造时尚的国家，
of in the countries where we manufacture the fashion,
同时也在时尚的窗口和品牌中，
but is also in the window of fashion, in the branding,
在，所有的通讯，呃，
in the, all the communication, uh,
在所有的通讯，嗯，情况。
in all the communication, um, situation.
对不起，我的手机，我还以为没事，我的手机
Sorry, my phone. I thought it, it was okay, my phone.
嗯，还有，
Um, and,
所以我们讨论了很多关于，
and so we discussed a lot about,
这样，作为活动家，
in which way, as activists,
我们一直在思考 不稳定性
we were working a lot in thinking about the precariousness
生命的不稳定性 总是要处理
of life, the precariousness of having always to deal
还有，嗯，
with the, um,
与临时工作。
with the temporary jobs.
在这个框架内 我们决定
And in this, uh, in this framework, we decided to
创建假时装设计师
create a fake fashion designer
进入时尚周的正式日历
that entered the official calendar of the fashion week
以某种方式扰乱
to somehow disrupt
并谴责对创造性工作者的剥削；
and denounce the exploiting of creative workers
在时尚周。
during the fashion week.
嗯，我们做到了
Um, we did it
因为我们有创造高质量技能
because we had the skills to create high quality
通讯和高质量的，嗯，设计。
communication and high quality, um, designs.
而且，呃，我们实际上创造了一个大事件
And, uh, we actually created a big event
于2005年举行。
in 2005.
因此，今年我们庆祝20年的活动。
So this year we celebrate 20 years of activity.
呃，在那次活动中，我们实际上
Uh, and during that event, we actually
这是一本书，
were reflecting, and this is a book,
谈论我们
talking, talking about us.
如果你想知道更多关于，
If you want to know more about the,
比如说一些学者的反射
the, let's say the reflection of some, uh, academics
围绕我们的工作。
around our work.
呃，我们创造了一个大事件 在，呃，我们
Uh, we created a big event in which, uh, we
呈现十件寓意的服装
presented the 10 allegorical garments to reveal
米兰创意产业的开发
the, the exploitation in the Milan creative industries.
但是我们首先创造了一个假的时装设计师
But we did it first creating a fake fashion designer
这适用于正式日历。
that applied to the official calendar.
然后当它被接受，
And then when it was accepted,
因为实际上 官方日历
because actually the official calendar
时尚周没有要求看任何衣服，
of the fashion week didn't ask to see any garment,
他们只是想要一些无关紧要的东西
they just wanted immaterial stuff.
他们想要那个品牌和商标
They wanted the, the brand, the trademark.
他们想要那本书 一本数字书
They wanted the, the book, a digital book
我们想要的设计
with all the designs that we wanted.
当然，我们没有，我们没有给他们这个，
Of course, we didn't, we didn't give them this one,
但我们给他们假的。
but we gave them fake.
我们做了一本假书，呃，看书。
We did a fake book, uh, look book.
做得很好，嗯，但用假衣服，
And that was well done, uh, and, um, but with fake garments,
我们被正式接纳，
and we were accepted officially,
我们创造了一个猫行道 而不是展示
and we created a catwalk in which instead of showing
我们在《望书》中介绍的正确的衣服，
the right garments that we presented in the Look book,
我们创造了这个寓言的服装
we created this allegorical garments
譬如说，你们看见衣服遮蔽着，
in which you see, for example, the garments to hide the,
为了掩盖怀孕
the, uh, to hide the pregnancy,
因为他们知道你怀孕了 他们就会解雇你
because where they know that you're pregnant, they fire you,
或者，像有双倍的工作，
or the, the job of like having double,
当你白天有双班时，你需要
when you have a double shift during the day, you need
白天换衣服，需要时换衣服
to change during the day or the garments when you need to.
他们要求一个女人 他们
They ask for a woman and they,
或者他们要求一个凸连接件， 接受这份工作。
or they ask for a male to be, to take the job.
所以我们做了这十件衣服
So we made this 10 garments in order to
我们的剥削正在发生
present in which way our exploitation was happening in,
在米兰
uh, in, in Milan.
但是，这是，呃，满人 因为我们创造了一个假。
But this was, uh, full of people because we created a fake.
嗯，还有，嗯，
Uh, also, um,
我们假装是...
we pretended that the activist of
米兰的场景正与这个设计师作对
the Milan scene were going against this designer
因为她假装
because she pretended
她向活动家提供了一些钱 来让猫行走
and she offered the activist some money to have the catwalk
在一个被占用的空间， 一个蹲下。
inside an occupied space, a squat.
这件事让记者非常好奇
And so this thing, uh, made the journalist very curious
来理解为什么
to understand why
以及为何活动人士之间发生争吵
and why there was this fight between the activists
和时装设计师， 但他们都是我们。
and the fashion designer, but both of them were us.
说来话长
So, I mean, it, it's a long story,
但你，你明白 主要的故事。
but you, you understand the, the, the main story.
然后，第二天，我们都加入了，
And the, the day after it was, we were all in,
所有报纸上都提到我们
in all the newspapers, and they talked about us
和工人在阴道上。
and workers on the catwalk.
嗯，我的意思是，有很多， 很多说话
Um, I mean, there was a lot of, a lot of talking
和八卦， 和大多数，嗯，
and gossiping, and most of the, um,
大多数报纸都提到我们
most of the newspapers talked about us,
但是时尚院发了一封信
but the Chamber of Fashion sent, um, a message
所有时尚杂志，
to all the fashion magazines to,
并告诉他们不要谈论我们
and told them not to talk about us
因为他们有， 他们觉得羞愧
because they had, they felt ashamed
他们接纳我们，
that they accepted us in the,
在正式日历中。
in the official calendar.
所以，我想 几年时间
And, and so I guess that a couple of years
在他们改变方式 申请时尚周，
after they changed the way to apply to the fashion week,
但从那时起，我们创造了，嗯，嗯，
but since then, we created, um, uh,
一个协会，一个开放的， 一个协会继续做
an association, an open, an association that kept doing
以沉思的服装盟誓，
and reflecting upon the garments that reflected upon,
嗯，如何使时尚的方式不同，
um, how to make fashion in a different way,
模式的开源方式
in which way the patterns could be open source
如何让人们学会如何制造东西。
and in which way people could learn how to make things.
我们还尝试了技术 比如说，一个
We also experimented with technology here, for example, one
我们的车间是...
of the, uh, workshop that we do is, uh,
制造激光切变速器
making laser cut stencil.
然后，我们，我们有 这些事件骑自行车，
And then we, we have these events of upcycling,
让你带着旧衣服来
so you can come with your old garments
你可以，呃， 创建自己的，呃， 骑自行车 作为骑自行车，
and you can, uh, create your own, uh, upcycling as upcycled,
穿着我们的设计
um, garment with our, uh, designs.
这是，你用卷 与丝印，呃，墨水，
This is, you use a roll with the silk print, uh, ink,
然后你就这么做了
and then you just did do it.
这就像发生，非常不错
And it's like happening. It's very nice.
最近我们打开，呃，
Recently we opened up, uh,
今年庆祝我们20岁的时候
actually this year to celebrate the 20th years we had,
我们在米兰有个画廊
we have a gallery now in Milan,
我们把它当作一个空的， 就像，它就像一个商店，
and we use it as an empty, like, it's like a shop,
我们用它做展览
and we use it to make exhibitions
并制作，邀请，呃，设计师
and to make, to invite, uh, designers
更生态 更道德
that are, uh, like more ecological and more ethical,
他们没有， 而且他们通常有小生产，
and they don't have, and they have usually small production,
他们没钱租米兰的店
and they don't have the money to rent a shop in Milan
因为它真的很贵。
because it's really expensive.
展览的租金也暴涨。
The rents for, also for exhibitions are skyrocketing.
所以，想法是，呃，
So the idea to was to make, uh,
新的社区空间
a community space in which to present, um, new
以时尚为重点的项目
projects that were focused on al fashion
以及一种新的时尚方法
and a new approach to, to fashion.
门开着，你可以加入社区来
And it's open. You can join the community and come
在米兰市中心展出
and exhibit in, in, in the center of Milan.
而这个想法其实在这10年，20年
And, uh, this idea actually in this 10 years, 20 years
我们所走的道路
of activity, the, the, the path that we took was
从黑客，黑客实践。
to move from the hack, the hacking practice.
黑客是说当你有了产品，
The hacking is about when you have a product,
当你们有一件事情，而你们不喜悦的时候，
when you have an object that you are not happy about it,
你黑它，所以你打破它 或者你，你，你打开它
you hack it, so you break it or you, you, you open it
你，这是一种反应的东西
and you, it's a kind of reaction of something
以免你们不喜悦，
that you are not happy with,
你做一个定制 也许，或
and you make a customization maybe, or an
或者打开一些东西来修复它。
or open up something to fix it.
所以这是第一个开放的行为。
So this is the first act of openness.
你打开物体，了解它是如何工作的，
You physically open the object, understand how it works,
你做一些改变。
and you make some changes.
然后我们进入第二阶段
Then we have the second phase
和关于制造 当数字化
and is about the making That started when digital
数字制造变得更加普及，
fabrication became more widespread,
而实际上就是发现，学习的态度，
and actually is the attitude to discover, to learn,
启动创建过程，我们说没用
activate processes for the creation of, we say useless
和有用的设备。
and useful devices.
因为很多
Because a lot
当你创造出无用的东西时， 学习就会降临
of learning comes when you also create useless
对象，因为你在这个过程中学习，你学习
objects, because you learn in the process, you learn
由你的错误， 这是，
by your errors, and this is,
你可以做到这一点 当你可以共享一个基础设施，
you can do it when you can share an infrastructure,
一个基础设施在一起。
an infrastructure together.
也是新思想原型化过程的一部分，
And it's a part of the process of prototyping new ideas,
造型的东西 通常是盈利
prototyping something that usually the for-profit
公司不生产。
companies are not making.
我们认为，这一增长的最后一步
And we think that the final step of this growth
考虑开放性就是开放式设计。
to think about openness is about open design.
这就是作为设计师的纪律
That is the, the discipline in which as a designer,
你们真的创造出对造物主友好的物体，
you really create objects that are maker friendly,
也就是说，他们可以数字化
that are, they can be digital
和物理设备嵌入潜力。
and physical devices embedded potential.
他们有潜力存在，设计
They have the potential in their being, in their design
修改，修改，由他人改进.
to be modified, to be fixed, to be improved by others.
采用系统的方法对待开放性也是一样。
So is a systemic way to approach openness.
我们认为，这是我们喜欢的设计。
And we think for us, this is the design that we like.
在 Serpica Naro 之后，我开始参与
Uh, after, uh, CICA narrow, I, I started
我的第一个开放，呃，呃，对不起，我的第一个，呃，
to make my first open, uh, uh, sorry, my first, uh,
一个欧盟资助的项目，叫作 Openwear。
um, EU funded project that it was open wear.
Openwear 项目是一种方式，
And this open wear project was, uh, a way to
把概念带给设计者
bring to the designers the concept
它来自 Serpica Naro 项目。
that came from Anaro project.
于是我们创建了一个新的开源品牌.
And so we created a new open source brand.
这个项目叫作 Openwear。
There's, that was called Open Wear.
我们合作收集的
We made a collaborative collection
我们创造了使用牌子的许可证
and we create a license to use the, the, the brand.
我们也分享了所有的规律。
And also we shared all the patterns.
大约在2009年，2009年和10年左右.
It was around 2009, 2009 and 10.
但从那几年起，问题是什么？
But what was the issue since in those years
之后我才意识到
that I realized only afterwards that most
在时尚学校接受教育
of the education in the fashion schools
就是用铅笔和纸来制作图案
was about making patterns by hand with pencil and paper,
很少有设计师 时装设计师知道如何画画
and very few designers, fashion designer knew how to draw
带有数字工具，带有数字软件.
with digital tools, with digital softwares.
因此我们没能形成足够的参与规模，
And so we couldn't reach the critical mass
让这个社区成长
to have this community to grow.
这就是为什么我真的很快乐
And that's why I'm really happy
这个学院正在发生
that this academy is happening
因为有很多缺乏。
because there is a lot of lack.
有很多缺乏知识
There is a lot of lack of knowledge
还有时尚上的技巧
and skills in the fashion.
嗯，学校围绕数字制造 现在有点，
Um, schools around digital fabrication now is a bit,
嗯，这有点好。
uh, it's a bit better.
呃，还有，还有，还有...
Uh, and one of the, also, the
我们所做的收藏是开源附件
collection that we did was open source accessories
和可穿戴的，是这种模式 数字化
and wearables that were this pattern that were digitalized
可以直接用在激光卡上
that could be used directly on the laser card.
有，它们是模板 你可以
There was the, they were the templates in which you could
从学习如何工作开始
start from learning how to work with
数字技术，特别是激光切割.
digital technology, and especially laser cut.
比方说，我们是在
This, for example, was a workshop that we did during
2000年米兰设计周.
Milan design week in 2000,
我认为是，呃，10或11。
and I think it was, uh, 10 or 11.
我们带来了激光切割 在设计周，
And we brought the laser cut in the, the design week,
我们当时觉得这双鞋很平坦
and we did with felt this shoes that were just flat,
但你可以，嗯， 折叠和缝合，
but you could, um, fold it and sew it,
并且对可穿戴技术的原型也有帮助。
and it was also useful to prototype wearable technology.
我做了这个工作坊，
I made this workshop,
所以我，我遇到了来自Arduino的Massimo Bandi。
and that's how I, I met Massimo Bandi from Arduino.
我带来了关于这个数字模式的知识。
I brought my knowledge about this digital pattern.
然后阿尔杜伊诺
And then Arduino
Massimo Banzi和学生一起工作。
and Massimo Banzi was working with students.
那是一所暑期学校，呃，和学生一起工作
It was a summer school, uh, was working with student in
开发和原型开源设备
developing and prototyping, um, open source devices
还有Lily Duino和另一个 以及其他的董事会
with, uh, Lily Duino and another, and other boards.
嗯，我帮助学生 做一个可穿的部分。
Um, and I was helping the student to make the wearable part.
嗯，稍后，我也和，呃，
Um, in later, I also talked to, uh,
在纽约的帕森斯学校
at the Parsons School in New York.
我被邀请来谈所有这些， 所有这些，呃，
I was invited to talk about all these, all these, uh,
我们的经历。
experiences that we made.
还有些纸
There is still some paper
和一本日记，如果你有兴趣的话。
and a journal around this if you are interested.
所以大家从这个想法开始
So all started with this idea
开放的定义，其实。
of openness definition, actually.
我当时在工作
Um, I was working
并活跃在，嗯，在， 在结尾
and being active in, um, in, at the end
像世纪。
of like the century.
所以98到99，我，呃，
So 98 to 99, I was, uh,
在米兰的黑客空间
in hacker spaces here in Milan.
在那些年，这是博客的术语，
And in those years, it was the term blogosphere,
我不知道，现在用得不多了
I don't know, it's not used so much now,
但是在那些年里，人们非常使用。
but in, in those years was very used.
这是第一个想法，呃，
It was the first idea of, uh,
其实是个新词，一个新词
it was actually a neologism, a new word
以表达互联网的真实性， 自我出版的博客
to express the real of the internet, self-published blogs
人们分享文字，图像
where people share the text, images
和链接，以便提前自由使用
and links in order to pre freely accessible
由他人阅读。
and read by others.
所以这个想法是在网上分享。
So this idea of sharing online.
所以这个想法
So the idea
从那时起，开放的概念就成为一种总括概念。
of openness has since then become an umbrella concept
提及增加知识的可获取性，
referring to increased accessibility of knowledge,
技术和其他资源。
technology and other resources.
但也代表了一种不同的方法
But also it came to signify, uh, a different approach
创造知识
to the production of knowledge itself.
因此促使我们思考行动的透明度
So pushing us to reflect on the transparency of action
承认
of any organization, recognizing that
为促进贡献的多样性，有必要
to foster the diversity of contributions, it was necessary
如何达到高渗透性的结构，
to reach a high permeability of structures, how
以何种方式作出决定，
to take decision in which way decision are taken within a,
机构
uh, institution.
所以这个新环境的政治意义开始
So the political implication of this new environment started
在黑客反文化中讨论，
to be discussed within the hacker counterculture,
从80年代中期开始就发生了
and it happened since the mid eighties, right,
自由的思想
where the ideas of free
和开源软件驱动最多
and open source software drove most
物质基础设施
of the material infrastructures
把互联网变成全球媒体
that turned the internet into a worldwide medium.
所以第一个开放的概念，
So the first concept of openness,
这是关于自由软件。
and it was about free software.
所以，呃，实际上，
And so, uh, actually,
自由软件基金会内的Richard Stahlman
Richard Stahlman within the Free Software Foundation
提出并推广了 Copyleft（著佐权）的概念。
invented and popularized the concept of copy left
和，嗯，嗯，这是一个法律机制
and the, um, uh, that is a legal mechanism
保护修改。
to protect the modification.
还有免费软件的发行权。
And there is distribution rights for free software.
所以他开始在哈佛大学学习
So he start, he studied at Harvard
后来成为麻省理工学院的程序员
and then became a programmer at MIT
加入黑客辩论，
joining the Hacker debate,
特别是澄清世界的意义。
especially clarifying the meaning of the world.
免费，所以自由软件是一回事
Free. Thus, free software is a matter
自由而不是代价
of liberty and not price.
这不仅仅是一个，不是
It is not just a, it is not
你只是下载免费软件，
that you just download free software,
但自由概念范围内的自由
but the, the, the, the liberty within the concept of free
更类似于言论自由的想法，
is more similar to the idea of free speech,
不是免费啤酒
not as free beer.
所以我们有时把它叫做Libre软件。
So we sometimes called it Libre software.
从法语中取出"Libre"这个词， 呃，呃，
Taking the word Libre from French and uh, uh,
自由也是一种自由 显示
and also free is a kind of freedom to show
我们并不意味着软件是免费的。
that we do not mean the software is gratis is for free.
所以，这个词的模糊性 自由，无论如何产生
So the ambiguity of the term free anyhow generated
很多误会
a lot of misunderstandings
和许多编译者选择使用替代
and many coders chose to use an alternative
开源
that is open source
因为它成为了一个更加广泛， 广泛，嗯，
because that became a more widespread, widespread, um,
而不是政治选择，
and less political option,
特别是在商业领域，
especially in the commercial field,
即使它有着许多共同的实用性
even if it shares many practical features
与自由软件。
with free software.
报告更加注重技术问题
It focuses more on the technical issues
软件开发
of software development
还避免围绕用户自由和道德的主题。
and also avoiding themes around user freedom and and ethics.
所以，这个概念 并没有给机会
So this, this concept than gave the opportunity
创建新的共享许可证
to create new licenses to share
一个可以在线分享的代码。
a piece of code that you can share online.
所以，他，他，这是一个表 你可以在网上找到。
So he, he, this is a table that you can find online.
所以，自由是自由的问题，而不是价格问题。
So free is a matter of liberty, not price.
打开并不意味着访问源代码自由引用
Open doesn't mean access to the source code free refers
价格，而使用的自由受到创作者的限制。
to price, while freedom of the use is restricted by creator.
所以有不同的许可证类型
So there are different type of licenses
你可以探险。
that you can explore.
最开放的是公有领域软件
And the most open one is, is the public domain software
属于整个公众，
that is belongs to the public as a whole,
它不涉及同样的版权规定。[识别疑点]
and it doesn't have any copyright law.
但我们也有一种新的许可证
But also we have a new type of licenses
是指数据上不同类型的内容。
that are referring to a different type of content on data.
所以，如果我们拿一个， 如果我们不谈论
So if we take a, if we don't talk about
软件，但我们想处理的内容
software anymore, but we want to deal with content
它的图片，任何内容 与创造力
and it's pictures, any content related to creativity
以及受版权或其他权利保护的内容，还有设计。
and covered by copyright or data, but also design.
因此，我们有更多的限制和
So we have more restrictive and
或限制程度较低的许可证持有者
or less re restrictive licensees
你可以选择 当你想要分享你的，
that you can choose when you want to share your,
嗯，这个想法。
um, idea.
你的时尚设计
Your design in fashion
其实有点不一样
actually is a bit different
讲师说，时装版型不受版权保护。[适用范围需核对]
because the pattern of fashion are not covered by copyright,
嗯，因为它是，呃，
uh, because it is, uh,
服务于纯粹的职能和目的。
serving purely a functional and purpose.
虽然法律
While the laws
不同的国家不同，变化很大。
is different in different country, it changes a lot.
所以，如果你想进入， 你可以遵循这个链接
So if you want to go into that, you can follow this link
探索你是否感兴趣
and explore if you're very interested.
有一些最佳做法。
There are some kind of best practices.
而且在，呃，
And in, uh,
最好，所以这个想法
ideally, so the idea
时尚行业的知识产权
of intellectual properties in the fashion industry actually
不仅因为它是实用主义的，而且因为
is not used, not just because it is utilitarian, but also
因为登记某件东西也是很困难的
because registering something is takes too
慢，太慢的时尚，
slow, is too slow for fashion,
因为你有很多作品
because you have a lot of production
每六个月发生一次
that happens every six months.
而且，呃，所以它没有跟上 短时间的趋势
And, uh, so it doesn't keep up with the shortlived trends
季节性收集。
of the seasonal collection.
所以通常使用的是商标。
And so what brand use usually is the trademark.
所以当你在某种东西上贴上商标，它就会变成
And so when you put a trademark on something, it becomes,
被某种知识产权所覆盖
uh, covered by a type of intellectual property
帮助不让，
that is helpful not to let the,
消费者应该对谁生产该物品感到困惑。
the consumer be confused about who is producing that object.
嗯，2011年，这本书
Um, the, in 2011, this book
它现在叫做Open Design，发布在，
that is called Open Design now, was published in,
嗯，呃，在荷兰的国土大厅，
um, in, uh, hall the Land in the Netherlands,
也仍然是很好的资源，如果你想
and also is still a nice resource if you want
探索设计师在想的
to explore in which way designer were thinking
创建与释放相关的新业务模式
to create new business model related to releasing
物体的蓝图，
blueprints of objects,
或者是时尚 可能是家具
or that could be fashion, that could be, uh, furniture
或任何有许可证的东西，
or anything under some kind of license,
鉴于有可能
given the possibility
和对他人进行数字修改的自由
and the freedom to others to digitally, um, modify
并在当地生产这些，嗯，类型的物体。
and locally produce these, um, type of objects.
所以，嗯，从开放的想法，呃，
So, um, from the idea of openness, uh,
我们也在这种 共同的想法
we moved also in this idea of the commons
因为这个开放的想法 我们，
because this idea of openness we,
我们之前讨论过的 与数字有关
that we talked about until now is really related to digital,
数字对象，你可以在网上分享的东西。
to digital objects, something that you can share online.
但当你移动到数字制造， 当你移动
But when you move to digital fabrication, when you move
给一些你做的东西，呃，
to something that you make physically, uh,
有些事情必须改变 有些事情必须...
something has to change, something has to, uh, be,
嗯，反射出来。
um, reflected upon.
所以实际上，数字制造变得非常广泛，
So actually, digital fabrication became very widespread,
特别是，呃，创造
especially for the, uh, the creation
两种主要工具。
of two main tools.
一个是阿诺控制器，Arduino控制器
One is the Arno controllers, the Arduino controllers
这很容易使用
that were very easy to use
内部使用价格可获取
and accessible in price were used inside
许多其他机器，例如3D打印机.
many other machine, like for example, 3D printers.
还有这个基础
And there were also on the base of this
和这个新对象的创建， 很多
and the creation of this new objects, a lot
出现了新的社区。
of new communities came up.
因此，制造空间的想法
So the idea of makerspace
和法伯拉布，我们做了杂志和交易会，
and FabLab, we had make magazine and maker fairs happening,
然后，呃，法布，呃，呃，
and then, uh, fab, uh, uh,
法布学院和，和，
fab academy and, and, and,
和，呃，法布会议发生，
and, uh, fab conferences happening,
但一切都开始了，特别是...
but all started, especially with the
开始和，呃，变得无障碍
beginning and the, uh, becoming accessible
三维打印技术。
of 3D printing technology.
所以，包装项目 是，我想说这是母亲
So the wrap wrap project was, I would say it's the mother
所有三维打印机， 重新包装，
of all the 3D printers, rep wrap,
意思是复制快速原型
meaning replicating rapid prototyping
因为它是一个倡议，
because it was an initiative that,
可以打印80%
uh, could print 80%
用于制造新机器的部件。
of the pieces that you could use to make a new machine.
所以，你实际上有 父母，嗯，3D打印机
So you actually had the parent, um, 3D printer
和孩子的三维打印机，
and the child 3D printer,
它运行在阿尔杜伊诺， 家庭树从这里，
and it was running on Arduino, the family tree from this,
你可以在维基百科上找到它，或者，
you can find it on Wikipedia or,
或者你能找到其他维基人
or some other wiki that you can find.
从文件的第一个例子
From this first example of documentation
这台机器在网上发布，很多
of this machine released online, a lot
所有机器开始复制。
of all the machines started to replicate.
你可以看到2006年的时间表
And so you can see the timeline from 2006
截至2011年12月31日的资产、负债、准备金和基金结余表
to 2011.
当然，我们还有10年
Of course, we had other 10 years,
但我只想说 这是第一个3D打印机
but I just to say that these were the first 3D printer
被创造的，
that managed to be created,
并不是他们都只是文件，
and not all of them were just documentation on,
互联网上，但他们成为了企业 将出售，
on internet, but they became businesses that would sell,
呃，你可以在网上买的包，然后，
uh, kits that you could buy online and,
并指示创建自己的 3D 打印机。
and with instruction to create your own 3D printer.
所以，呃，在同样的年份，
So, uh, in the same years,
还有另一个思想家叫UI银行
there is this other thinker that is called yo, um, UI Bank.
他写了"网络财富"
Uh, he wrote the Wealth of Network,
而这位教授 他创造了这个通用术语
and this professor, he created this term common based
同行制作，描述在何处和
peer production to describe wherever and
只要人们自由结社
whenever people freely associate
并创造数字公用，
and create digital commons together,
成为共享资源
which then become shared resources that are maintained
社区或利益攸关方团体
by a community or a group of stakeholders
通过其自己的规则和规范。
through their own rules and norms.
同行方面是指开放程度，
The peer aspect refers to the level of openness,
或者说，人的能力
or rather the capacity of people
加入这些开放的价值创造网络而不要求
to join these open networks of value creation without asking
获得正式许可。
for formal permission.
因此，这个想法 分享所有的知识，
So this idea of sharing all the knowledge,
没人问你是谁？
no one ask you who are you?
你是设计师吗？
Are you a designer? Are you an engineer? No, anyone.
你可能会在你的家里。
You could be in your home.
你可以是学生，你可以下载所有
You could be a student, you can download all the
文档，您也可以复制自己的3D打印机。
documentation and you can replicate your own 3D printer.
你有问题，你在论坛上写
You have any issue, you write on the forum,
你加入一个社区，没有人，
you join a community, no one,
你不需要请求许可。
you don't need to ask permission.
因此，在这个，在这个想法
So, and in, in this, in this idea
不要求许可，也意味着你可以
of not asking for permission, it means also that you can
也可以创造某种经济
also create, um, you can create some kind of economy.
事实上，对等基础
And in fact, that the peer-to-peer foundation,
那是另一个非营利组织
that is another, uh, nonprofit organization
和致力于这一想法的全球网络
and global network that is dedicated to the, this idea
制造业生产
of common oriented, uh, manufacturing production
或解决方案。
or solutions.
他们写道，我们相信一种新类型
They wrote, we believe that a new type
开放设计相结合，
of economy will be evolving whereby open design are combined
具有分布性物质生产，能力
with distributed physical production, the capability
由个人，设计者生产设计，
by individuals, designers to produce design,
由3D 打印机以物理格式制作
have them produced by 3D printers in a physical format
并有机会接触当地
and with access to local
或经销商生产这些产品。
or distributor labor for producing them.
所以，不知何故，一个新的经济出现了
So somehow a new economy came out
其中，一个新的经济
of this, a new economy
以开放设计原则为基础。
that is based on open design principle.
所以有，呃，一个反射
So there there's been, uh, a reflection
提出一个开放的设计定义。
of coming up with a open design definition.
所以，开放设计是设计文物
So open design is a design artifact
其文献公开，呃，
whose documentation is publicly available, uh,
不仅如此
but also, uh, is not just that.
不只是你公布文件 还不够
It is not just that you publish the file, it's not enough,
但是，它应该制造，或者应该创造。
but it, it should be made or it should be created.
您应该使用随时可用的组件创建它
You should create it using readily available components
和材料、标准流程、开放基础设施
and materials, standard processes, open infrastructures
并限制内容
and restrict content
和开源数字工具，以最大限度地提高能力
and open source digital tool to maximize the ability
个人制造和使用硬件。
of individuals to make and use hardware.
所以，现在，一个平台 真正推动
So right now, one of the platform that is really pushing
并围绕此创建事件
to make this happen and create an event around this
，是分布式设计项目在
and is the distributed design project in
他们出版的地方
where they're publishing
和理解 如何有，呃，
and understanding in which way there is, uh,
应该有一个生态系统来做这个，嗯，
there should be an ecosystem to make this, um,
嗯，新世界的物体发生。
um, new world of objects happen.
因为让我们记住这些事情，
Because let's remember these things,
这种新生态系统不会发生 如果你工作
this type, this new ecosystem don't happen if you work
一个人呆在家里就别这样
alone, don't happen if you just stay in your home
你只是做你的东西。
and you just do your things.
和同龄人建立网络关系 建立网络关系
It's really important to network with peers, to network
跟像你这样的人
with other people like you
共享基础设施，共享知识。
and to share infrastructure, to share knowledge.
2005年时，嗯，
And, and in 2005, um,
这么多年了，我们想想开放
after all these, let's say years of thinking about openness,
我们有这个想法
we have this idea
爆炸，从良好的意义上来说，呃，
and the, the explosion in the good sense of, uh,
全球网络中的 Mamerspace 和 FabLab.
makerspace and FabLab in a global network.
还有数字制造的想法
And the idea of digital fabrication
从刚刚开始，你有输入设计，嗯，
move from being just, you have an input design, uh,
一个文件，你共享文件，
a file, you share the file,
然后把它放在三维打印机里
and then you put it in a 3D printer,
对象为某种类型
and you have your object in some type
在交互式制造中，设计者并非唯一的
of interactive fabrication in which the designer is not the
创造物体的人，
person that creates the objects,
设计师就是那个人
but the designer, it is the person
创建接口、框架
that creates an interface, a framework
可被用户修改的参数设计
of a parametric design that can be modified by the user
达到，达到的能力
to reach the, the ability
以小变化表示对象。
of the object in term of small changes.
然后，你可以点击一个按钮
And after that, you can click a button
，并通过该类型命令对象
and order the object through that type
用于定制和个性化的预制物体。
of fabricated object that is customized and personalized.
这种交互式制造在某种程度上
Uh, and the, this interactive fabrication somehow
曾经是，呃，一直
is the one that has been, uh, has been
庆祝许多变化
celebrating a lot of change
和很多有趣的项目
and a lot of in interesting projects
绕着它，只是 设定这个，呃，
around it just to frame this, uh,
设想这一方法，在
envision this approach in a, in a,
在更长的时间内。
in a longer period of time.
如果我们想到制造
If we think of manufacturing
以及工业前生产
and production from the pre, uh, pre-industrial
在这场革命中，我们在当地举办了讲习班，
revolution in which we had local workshop in which
你有手艺
you had craft
和造物的实验室，
and craft lab creating objects,
我们进入中央
we move into the centralized
第一次工业革命，
on the first industrial revolution,
第二次工业革命，
the second industrial revolution,
第三次工业革命
the third industrial revolution in which
所有生产仍然非常集中。
all the production is still very centralized.
它改变的是能力，
What it changes is the capacity of,
嗯，不要浪费太多的时间 设置
uh, not wasting too much time in setting up
生产，生产。
the, the, the production.
然后，呃，你移动你
And, uh, you move you
你们的产品成本很低，你们有，
and you have a low cost of the products, and you have,
但你有很高的数字
but you have high number
并且你能够真正控制
and you can really control
生产也取决于
the production also depending on
消费者最后消费的东西
what the consumer is consuming in at the end
，但仍然是线性
of the supply chain, but is still linear
还有，呃，不是
and is also, uh, not
非常适合最终用户。
very fitted on the final user.
我们喜欢的新情况
What we like about the new situation
而我们所认为的机会是第一个工业
and what we see as an opportunity is the first industrial
革命是因为你可以有 本地工厂，
revolution because you can have local factory that,
技术水平很高
that are very high, uh, high um, technology.
他们，他们可以包含高科技 像机器人，
They, they can contain high technology like robots,
但设置成本并不高
but the setup cost is not super high.
你可以创造出多种产品
And you can create many type of products
可以定制面具，而且，
that can be mask customized and,
特别是，嗯，专注
and is especially, um, focused
并通过开放式设计和数据引导设计进行管理。
and managed through open design and data led design.
嗯，当然， 当我们制造物体，
Um, of course, when we make objects,
这意味着我们需要使用材料
it means that we need to use materials
我们该使用哪种材料？
and which type of materials should we, shall we use,
这不是我们不能想到的事情。
is not something that we cannot think about.
目标之一
And one of the objectives
城市全球主义倡议
of the fab city globalist initiative is also
来理解我们的城市会变成怎样
to understand in which way our cities could become
我们能生产的地方
places in which we can produce
几乎所有我们，我们消费的地方，
almost everything that we, that we consume locally,
当然不是
of course, is not something
我们可以在10年内创造，
that we can create in like 10 years,
但这需要几年的时间
but it's something that it will take some years.
但这个想法是，我们可以
But the idea is that we can
全球份额
share globally
并在当地利用材料资源生产
and produce locally taking the resources of materials
我们能在当地找到
that we can find locally
并找到重新使用可视为废物的方法。
and find ways to reuse what could be considered waste.
而这里我们回去， 当然，你没有，
And here we go back, of course, you don't,
你不应该仅仅想到城市，
you shouldn't think just of the city,
但是，例如，我告诉你的项目，
but for example, the project that I told you about,
关于羊毛，这是，这是，这是 我尝试的东西
about the wool, this is, this is something that I'm trying
适用于我们拥有的农村地区，
to apply in a rural area in which we have,
有一个资源是物质，
there is a resource that is a material,
我们可以利用数字制造 在当地创造
and we could use digital fabrication to create locally
当地人可以消费的产品，
product that can be consumed by local people,
因为现在这很重要
because now it's really important
思考供应链。
to think about the supply chain.
如果我们不这样做，我们就不能做出可持续的东西
We cannot make something that is sustainable if we don't
反思供应链和这一供应链。
reflect upon the supply chain and this supply chain.
当然，我们知道循环是一种，
Of course, we know that circularity is a kind of,
而且，我们有很多 绿色洗在 我们知道
also, we have a lot of greenwashing in that we know
大部分塑料无法回收。
that most of the plastic cannot be recyclable.
呃，我不会去那个，
Uh, I'm not going into that,
但把注意力集中在材料上是非常重要的
but it is really important to focus on the material
你们用什么做市场，
that you use and what are the marketplace
这种新型产品。
of this new type of products.
基于开放的新产品
The new products that are based on openness
和微型工厂。
and micro factories.
我们称之为长尾模型
It's what we call the long tail model
这可以帮助你理解如何定位我们的产品。
that can help you understand how to position our products.
因此，如果我们考虑 特殊产品，一个
So if we consider the niche products, the one
这是奢侈品，高端与，嗯，
that are luxury, high-end with, um,
有很多，嗯， 也像工匠做的，
with many, uh, also like craftsmen making it,
如果他们是高大的，
that if they are made by high,
主流品牌是高档产品
uh, mainstream brand are highly products,
却以特产制作，
but made in niche products,
我们可以把自己定位在 这种流行
we can position ourself in this sort of kind of popular
在其中创建独特的产品
in which there are unique products that are created
且可本地定制， 其中有许多类型
and customizable locally, in which there are many type
能够根据需求创造的产品
of products that can be created on demand
特定领土。
on specific territories.
嗯，所以一些例子，呃，
Um, so some example, uh,
其中一个，我的意思是，这个项目是，不是，呃，
one of, I mean, this project is, is not, uh,
这已经行不通了 但还是个很好的例子
is is not working anymore, but it's still a nice example.
已经十年了 我喜欢他们的做法
I mean, it is 10 years. Uh, I liked their approach.
所以我给你一个例子
And so I give you, I give you this an, an example,
但它也理解在下面，是不错的
but it's also understand is under, is nice
来理解为什么它不起作用。
to understand why it does it didn't work.
呃，所以，呃，他们分享，嗯，
Uh, so, uh, they shared, um,
激光切割，嗯，设计在
laser cut, um, designs in
可以在本地制造厂里生产
that could be produced in, um, in local maker spaces.
因此，他们还创建了制造器空间网络
So they create also network of maker spaces
它可以生产这些，呃，衣服。
that could produce these, uh, garments.
嗯，另一个有趣的项目 你可以看看
Um, another project that is interesting that you can look
通过是开放的鞋。
through is the open footwear.
呃，我，我最近，我刚刚，
Uh, I, I'm recently,
我最近穿着赤脚鞋
I'm recently using barefoot shoes,
所以我很想知道 尝试这个新的方法
and so I'm really curious to try this new approach to
光脚，这里还有一只鞋
barefoot also here it's a shoe
你可以在制造空间制造。
that you can make in a makerspace.
嗯，然后我们有Atak，即，呃，
Um, then we have Atak that is, uh,
他们创建一个区域的项目
a project in which they created an area
名为“共享”的网站
of the website that is called Shareware
你可以探索，他们制造，
that you can explore and they made,
他们分享了一些很好的模式
and they're sharing some nice pattern
你可以下载。
that you can download.
你可以给，呃，一些贡献，
You can give like, uh, some contribution,
也可以免费下载。
but also you can download them for free.
他们建议价格 但你可以免费下载
They suggest a price, but you can download it for free
很高兴，嗯，作为一个起点
and it's nice to, uh, as a starting point
以探索开源模式。
to explore open source pattern.
还有一个，这是3D卡莫 是一件连帽衫，其中
There is also, this is a 3D camo is a hoodie in which
你买一个建筑包
you buy a construction kit
你可以，嗯，编曲
and you can, um, compose
把你的连衣帽装在家里
and assemble your hoodie at home
并且正在输，正在使用交叉
and is losing, is using interlocking
正如你在本周的演习中所做的那样。
as you will do in this exercise of this week.
我喜欢 Atacac 定价模式的一点是
But what I like about attack C price model is that
他们的价钱越来越高，因为你，
they have an increasing price in, in the sense that you,
如果你预先订购， 你支付，呃，
if you pre-order, you pay, uh,
66%的价格。
66% of the price.
如果它在生产， 然后，它继续。
If it's in production, it then the, it goes on.
和这股，如果它是在库存。
And this stock, if it's in stock.
所以，这意味着如果你已经订购，
So that means if you already order,
如果他们已经生成了对象，
if they already produce the object,
你会付出百分之百的代价，因为，
you're gonna pay the a hundred percent of price because,
这个想法不错 真正思考
and this is a nice idea to really think also
生产，呃，方式，
of the production, uh, ways, the,
按需生产的方式
the ways in which on demand production can happen
在短，呃，
on short, uh,
或小批量，嗯，生产可以是，可以使用
or small batches of, um, production can be, can be used
这很有趣，呃，
that are interesting, uh,
因为我们来自一个
because we come from a world in which
价格是固定的。
the price is fixed.
但我觉得
But somehow I think
我们正处在一个重要的时刻
that right now we are in a moment in which it's important
真正，嗯， 让我们说，有益的人
to really, um, let's say benefit people
给该项目带来了一些支持。
that are bringing some support to the project.
带一些支持意味着，呃，
And bringing some support means, uh,
有信念的东西 和预先订购
having faith on something and pre-ordering
以物配主，
and being transparent also with the price,
向人们展示我们的方式，呃，我们的方式，
showing people in which way we are, uh, in which way we are,
嗯，组成价格
um, composing the price
我们卖的东西。
of the object that we sell.
嗯，回到材料，
Um, going back to the materials,
也感谢欧盟的新规则
it's, uh, thanks also to the new rules by European Union.
当然了，我指的是欧盟
Of course here we, I'm talking about European Union
因为我住的地方。
because that's where I live.
还有很多新的规范
And, and there are new, a lot of new norms
关于可持续性。
regarding sustainability.
而如今品牌不能随意扔掉或焚烧剩余产品。[法规范围见笔记]
And now brands cannot throw away or burn leftovers.
这么多
So a lot
网络上的新店铺正在出现 你可以找到
of new shops online are happening in which you can find
留下的纺织品。
leftovers of textiles.
这个非项目，嗯，
This non project is, um,
一个时尚的大集团，呃，嗯，
a big conglomerate of fashion, uh, um,
这么说吧
oh, let's say
在那里，他们出售其纺织品的剩余部分。
platform in which they sell the leftovers of their textile.
所以这是非常高质量的好，
So it's really high quality good,
它花费，呃，一个分数比较
and it cost, uh, a fraction compared
直接购买
to buying it directly.
这是新设计师的机会
And this is the opportunity that new designers,
当代设计师可以联系
contemporary designers can have to reach
优质纺织品，无
high quality textile without having
花费太多。
to spend too much.
你不只是用纺织的
You don't have it only with textile,
但你也可以带着皮革
but you can have it also with leather.
所以，呃，法国，呃，平台允许你
So this, uh, French, uh, platform allows you to
主要购买皮革残渣.
buy leftovers of leather mainly.
他们也有一些布料，
They also have some fabrics,
但他们正在找回所有剩下的东西
but they are recovering all the leftovers from
与皮革合作的公司。
companies that are working with leather.
这样你就可以买一些碎片给
And so you can buy some pieces to
制作自己的，呃，有限版对象。
make your own, uh, limited edition objects.
就像，呃，这是一个例子 我一直在工作，呃，
Like, uh, this is one example I've been working, uh,
在过去几年，呃，关于想法
in the past years of, uh, on ideas
微型工厂的想法
of micro factories, the idea
微小工厂关于从数字设计转移
of micro factories about moving from a digital design
对定制产品，
of a customized product,
客户进入商店的自定义产品
customizable product in which a client enter the shop
并且你感谢技术，对象
and you make thanks to technology, the the object
直接在商店里
directly in the store.
我想给你看个视频
I wanted to show you a video.
我的意思是，有一个声音，但我的意思是，
I mean, there is a sound, but I mean,
所以这里的想法是有一个家庭的袋子
So here the idea was having a family of bags
这可以做到。
that could be made.
所以你想象一个客户进入商店
So you imagine a client that enters the shop
选择皮革的颜色。
chooses the color of the leather.
所以，我们像一个吊架 有很多不同的颜色
So we have like a hanger with many different colors
皮革残渣
of leather leftovers.
你当然会选一个，我们用激光切割
Of course you choose one, we laser cut the part
这就是，让我们说加薪， 然后我们附加它，
that is the, let's say the the raise, and then we attach it,
然后选择膀胱绳
and then you choose the bladder cord
你拥有，嗯，
and you have the, um,
包直接编织
weaving of the bag directly.
所以，我们，在一个小时内 你可以创建你的篮子，
So we, in one hour you can create your basket,
你的车篮，皮革回来。
your bus basket, leather back.
所以这个想法来了
So this idea came
因为这个想法
because this idea
(a) 向希望获得服务的公司提供服务；
of having a service for companies that wanted to
有自己的店铺 直接做
have their own shop to make directly
一个物品，商店里的附属物，
an object, an accessory in the store,
我们可以把服务卖给客户
and we could sell this service to clients.
嗯，那这是，
Um, so what is the,
这个想法
the, the idea
以及我们希望提供的备选模式
and the alternative model that we want to provide
我们想，呃，实验？
and we want to, uh, experiment with?
我们想找出
And we want to figure out in which
如果在城里，这样是可能的
way this can be possible if in the city,
如果在乡下移动
if in the countryside is to move
从传统的想象方式
from the traditional way to conceiving
时尚附庸或时尚产品。
a fashion accessory of a fashion or a fashion product.
而且，呃，我们想这样做 从
And, uh, we want to do this moving from
停止想象产品的想法，
stop conceiving the idea of the product,
但是，嗯，想象一个
but, um, conceiving a
而不是一个产品 一个家族，呃，
platform instead of a product, a family of, uh,
产品数量
of products with the same, more
或更少相同的设计， 一个强有力的想法可以，呃，打开
or less the same design, a strong idea that can, uh, open up
对不同类型的定制。
to different type of customization.
与其考虑季节性采集，不如想想
Instead of thinking of seasonal collection, you can think
基于开放代码的不断发展的目录
of an evolving catalog based on open codes
和开放。
and the openness.
开诚布公的想法不是，我同意我的设计
The idea of openness is not about, I share my design
所以人们可以免费做
so people can really make it for free.
我的意思是，你会喜欢 人们做免费
I mean, you would love that people make it for free
因为通常当你分享的时候，只有1%
because usually when you share it, only 1%
人们正在这样做。
of people are doing it.
所有其他人，如果他们喜欢，他们买它。
All the others, if they like, they buy it.
还有这个想法
And also this idea of
大众生产，唯一的方法
mass production, the only way
阻止污染是，嗯，
to stop the pollution of the is, um,
时尚行业是限制
the fashion industry is to limit
大规模生产和移动
mass production and move
生产量或小批量生产量。
to an on demand or small batches production.
因此，我们没有剩下的， 我们不必燃烧，
So we don't have leftovers, we don't have to burn,
我们不需要喜欢丢弃
we don't have to like throw away
我们不用回收
and we don't have to recycle
因为所有这些都不利于地球。
because all these are not good for the planet.
所以在商店的销售， 这个想法，我们知道
So distribution in stores, this idea, we know
当我们移动，当成本
that when we move, when the cost
例如，我们为生产物体而付出的代价，
that we pay to produce an object, for example,
你生产一个袋子
you produce a bag
从想法到制作 成本
and from the idea to the production, it cost
商店里的生活费用是一百欧元
life cost is a hundred euros in the store,
费用是三四百元
the cost will be 300 or 400.
因为每K店里要买东西
Because having something in the shop costs per k,
因为店铺成本高 交了很多税
because the shops have high costs, pay a lot of taxes,
他们有个人整天呆在店里
they have someone to stay in the store all day.
所以这不是什么，因为他们贪婪，
So it is not something that, because they're greedy,
但你真的需要很多， 你需要很多，嗯，
but really you need a lot of, you need a lot of, um,
开店费
expenses to have a store.
所以降低价格的一个办法是卖掉
So one solution to have lower prices is to sell
直接在线或本地创建
directly online or locally creating
或许你有地方
situation in which maybe you have a place
在那里你可以储存你的原型， 你的模板，
where you can store your prototypes, your templates,
然后人们上线
and then people go online
并订购一个版本，一个定制版本。
and order a version, a customized version.
所以，这样的话，你可以和别人合作去做。
So, and this, you can do it in collaboration with others.
这就是为什么我总是说 你需要联网。
That's why I always say you need to network.
你需要贡献和与他人合作。
You need to contribute and collaborate with others.
而不是有风险资本来资助
And instead of having venture capital to fund
很多，呃，很多时候
a lot of, uh, in a lot
我们的人群资助
of situations we have crowdfunding
或预售有效。
or pre-selling that works.
所以，你推出的产品 像我给你的例子，
So you launch a product like the example that I gave you,
你有，你还有，呃，
and you have and you have, uh,
客户订购它 因为你知道你准备好了。
clients that are ordering it because you know you're ready.
你创造了一个社区的人 知道，
You created a community of people that know,
知道你的工作 因为你也分享设计
know about your work because you also share the design.
所以，比有喜欢， 像公司
So more than having like, like a company
考虑一下物体
that just think about the, the object
而发行是一类用户群
and the distribution is a kind of community of users
和支持您工作的早期用户
and early users that support your work
并准备在
and are ready to give a contribution when
当你们生产，当你们生产，
and when you produce and when you manufacture.
这样，我认为有一些成分
And in this way, I think there are some ingredients
你可以从创造自己的想法。
that you can take from to create your own ideas.
非常感谢
And thank you very much.
如果你有任何疑问，我会停止分享。
If you have any question, I will stop sharing.
可能有些问题
Probably there are some questions
或
or
哈罗
Hello.
哇 心脏有很多标志
Wow. Hearts a lot of logos.
要不要我检查一下问题的页面？
Mm. Shall I check the page of the question? Okay.
是任何人，呃，不是，呃，亚历克斯，
Is anyone, uh, not, uh, Alex,
我能问个问题吗？
Can I ask a question?
对，我很好奇
Yes. I'm curious.
我看到年轻人的复兴
I see a renaissance in young people
想学缝纫
wanting to learn how to sew.
这些，嗯，嗯， 这些，呃，思考的方式
Would any of these, um, uh, these, uh, ways of thinking
包括引进人来制造
of manufacturing include bringing people in to make some
为了让大家接受训练？
of the parts themselves so that people could be trained in?
是的，手艺，
Yes, handcraft,
对，当然有
Yes, of course there is somehow
您可以真正设计您的产品，其中
you can really design your products in which
也许你已经卖一包了
maybe you already sell a kit of pieces.
还有完成某些部分的工具。
That with also the tools to finish some parts.
但重要的是，呃，网上的辅导，
But the important thing is to have, uh, tutorials online,
也许录影带 如何做到这一点，
maybe a video on how to do it,
或者你可以用激光切割 真正说，
or maybe you can use the laser cut to really say in which,
把针放哪里，你知道，
where to put the needle, you know,
因为有时它， 有一个，
because sometimes it, there is a,
当你创造一些东西的时候，你感到失望
you feel disappointed when you create something
然后当你看到它说， 哦，我的手，不是那么好。
and then when you see it say, oh, my hand, were not so good.
所以作为设计师 你必须做到
And it is bad. So you as a designer, you have to make it
尽量方便最后的客户
as easy as possible in order to the final customer
做一些好事，这就是目标
to make something that is good, that is the objective
设计者，设计者的目的
of the designer, the, the purpose of the designer to
简化进程以完成。
simplify the process in order to do it.
所以，当，呃，有一个项目，呃，
So when, uh, there is, uh, a project
这叫另一只鞋，呃，
that is called another shoe that is, uh,
就像十年前我们在那里做过一样
like also there 10 years ago in which we did it in,
我们做了另一只鞋的车间 你可以做
we did a workshop of this other shoe that you could make
用激光切割。
with laser cut.
他们来到我的制造空间
And they were coming to my makerspace
他们正在测试用户
and they were testing with users
他们是如何组装鞋。
how they were assembling the shoes.
所以在推出产品之前 他们正在做一些事情
So before launching the product, they were doing some kind
如何，如何，如何困难
of focus group and see how much the, how, how is difficult
对我来说，因为也许作为一个设计师 你觉得很简单，
to me because maybe as a designer you think is easy,
但你试了一下，然后组成一个团体
but then you try it and make a, a group
你测试一下，然后说，天啊，不。
and you test it and say, oh my god, no.
你可以看到人们如何解释教程
And you can see how the people interpret the tutorial
指引，看看结果是什么。
guidelines and see what is the outcome.
因此，它帮助你作为一个设计师起草和，
And so it helps you as a designer to draft and,
并创建一个正在真正运行的教程
and create a tutorial that is really going
走向正确的方向 实现人民，人民
to the right direction to fulfill also the, the people
他们的手不太对劲
that are not really good with their hands.
谢谢
Thank you.
还有别的问题吗？
Any other question? Don't be shy.
谢谢你的演讲 非常鼓舞人心
Uh, thanks for the lecture. It was very inspiring.
我想问一些你提到的项目
I wanted to ask, some of the projects that you mentioned
以欧洲联盟为基地的
that are, uh, based in the European Union are mostly
或部分政府，呃，资助。
or in part government, uh, funded.
我想知道你是否对 呃
I'm curious to know if you have an opinion on, uh,
我们能做什么 在各国
what can we do on in countries
或你知道，地点
or you know, places
我们没有这种支持
where we don't have this kind of support.
像是什么风景 看起来像，看起来像
Like what is the landscape looking like, looking like
其他人在干嘛？ 这样我们就能办到？
and what are others doing so we can, uh, make this work?
好吧，所以是的，嗯，当然。
Okay, so yes, um, for sure.
我的意思是，不是所有的东西
I mean, not all the things
我给你看的是政府资助
that I showed you are government funded.
所以，所以有些，嗯，例如，
So, so some of them, um, for example,
当我在米兰建立我的制造空间时
the, when I set up my makerspace in Milan,
没有资金。
there was no funds.
所以我只好去跟人谈谈，做一些事情
So I had to go and talk with people, make events
与想投资制造空间的人战斗
and fight people that would like to invest in a maker space.
所以我们把资源集中起来。
And so we put together the resources.
所以这个想法是看你的国家有什么
So the idea is to see what do you have in your country
那能支持你吗？
that could support you?
有时他们可以给你一些技术资金。
Sometimes they can give you some funds for technology.
他们给你一些资金 比如，呃，我不知道，空间。
They give you some funds for like, uh, I don't know, spaces.
有许多事情你需要启动一个项目。
There are many things that you need to start a project.
所以，当你缺少的东西， 你可以有其他的东西。
So when you lack on something, you can have on other things.
但是，在进入一个企业之前，呃，
But before launching into a venture that, uh,
那需要钱是很好的测试它，
that needs money is good to test it in,
在一个小环境中，例如这个想法
in m in a small environment, for example, this idea
鞋子，比如说，你设置之前
of the shoe, for example, you before setting up
并购买激光切割，你可以去
and buying a laser cut, you can go
并拥有制造空间和试验的成员，以及
and have a membership in a maker space and test and, and
和原型，物体。
and prototype the, the objects.
然后当你有一个非常强烈的概念，
And then when you have a very strong concept,
你可以开始，呃，像 冒险
you can start, uh, like the venture
在制造空间 只有生意结束，你才能说
in a makerspace and only when the business goes you can say,
好吧，我可以买我自己的激光切割 因为它的工作。
okay, I can buy my own laser cut because it works.
所以总有一步一步的
So there is always step by step,
这在很大程度上取决于理解
and it depends a lot on understanding in
他们给你的祖国。
what they give you in your country.
有时他们会给你加速程序
Sometimes they give you acceleration programs,
有时他们会给你很多东西
sometimes they give you, I dunno, many things.
有钱总是有的
There are always money is out there.
所以不知何故 钱 钱 不是他们给你钱的手段
So somehow money, money, not the means they give you money,
但是在意义上的资源空间， 知识共享，
but resources in the sense spaces, knowledge sharing,
机器分享，嗯，这些类型的东西。
machine sharing, um, these type of things.
通常不会单独工作
Usually there are so never work alone.
你应该找到阿里的
The you should, you should find some Ali.
谢谢，谢谢，佐伊
Thank you. Thank you, thank you Zoe.
嗯，呃，我们可以，嗯， 现在继续，呃，
Uh, uh, we can um, now move on, uh,
因为我们必须继续
because we will have to continue
说明中技术性较强的部分。
with the more technical part of the presentation.
嗯，但是，嗯，是的，许多。
Um, but um, yeah, many.
好的，谢谢，谢谢
Okay, thank you. Yes, thank you.
所以我下周会去，呃，审查一下工作
So I will be next week in, uh, reviewing the work.
好的，下周二见
Yes. Okay. See you next Tuesday.
好的，非常感谢
Okay. Thank you very much.
如果你有任何问题
And if you have any questions,
帮我写封邮件什么的
just write me an email or whatever.
好的，祝你一周愉快，再见
Okay. Have a good week. Bye-bye.
谢谢 再见
Thank you. Bye. Yeah, bye. So,
好吧，我想你可以看到我的屏幕。
Okay, I think you can see my screen.
呃，告诉我如果你听不见我。
Uh, let me know if you cannot hear me.
我今天的关系没那么好
My connection is not that great today.
因此，我认为是时候继续 更实际的部分
So I think it's time to move on with the more practical part
本公开源代码的时尚讲座
of this open source circular fashion lecture
将侧重于一体化
that will focus on an integration
特别是数字制造技术。
with the digital fabrication technologies specifically.
又一次，激光切割。
Once again, the laser cut.
所以今天在这个演讲中，我们将谈论，嗯，
So today in this presentation we'll talk about, um,
版型、材料、织物，当然还有数字设计。
patterns, materials, fabrics, and of course digital design.
具体来说，我们将集中，嗯，无缝模式。
Specifically, we will focus, um, seamless patterns.
所以，我们探索，嗯，服装系统
So we'll exploring, um, clothing systems
可以设计为模块化，适应性，呃，
that can be designed to be modular, adaptable, uh,
可以重塑，当然可以拆解
reconfigurable and of course designed to be disassembled.
我们看看许多应用的意向
We we'll have a look at aspirations at many applications at
最新技术，当然项目
the state of the art, and of course at project
你可能已经根据我们开放的目录
that you may be already based on our open catalog
这是开源 秘密时尚。
that is open source secret fashion.com.
还有很多项目
That also many projects
过去九年中完成的工作
that have been done in this past nine years
Fabricademy 的作品，以及其他贡献者的作品。
of fabric academy, but also from people that contributed
离开社区。
that were outside of the community.
这其实就是
And this is actually the location where
本周之后， 您的创建将被上传 。
after this week your creation will be uploaded.
当我们，嗯，看图案，我也想要
When we, um, look at the patterns, I also want
带回来一些东西。
to bring back a couple of things.
所以我在演讲中强调了 2025年
And so I highlighted in the presentation, so it's 2025,
我们都知道是时候了
and we all know that it's time
重新思考我们消费的方式，我们生产
to rethink the way we consume, we produce
我们处理材料，呃，货物
and we dispose materials, uh, goods
特别是时尚
and specifically fashion.
所以我们都在世界不同的地方
So we are all in different locations of the world
我们仍然被垃圾包围 但垃圾填埋场
and we're still all surrounded by trash, but landfills
和时尚洗涤，呃，这个老的，嗯，模型
and fashion scrubs, uh, this older the, um, model
获取、使用和丢弃材料
of taking, using and discarding materials
这真的工作了。
that really work anymore.
试着拥抱这个概念
So trying to embrace here, um, this concept
循环经济，这就是我们，
of circular economy, this is what we,
我们真的应该考虑一下
we should really take into account.
因此，试图保持材料的使用 长久
So trying to keep the material in use for as long
尽可能地，做衣服 很容易，嗯，
as possible and making clothes that can easily, um,
修补完 继续 关闭循环
repaired, remained, um, closing the loop so
没有什么会真的浪费
that nothing really goes to waste
只有这种模式。
and only this patterns.
用这种衣服
With this kind of clothing
和系统，我想给你们看一对夫妇
and systems in mind, I would like to show you a couple
原则和方法
of principles and approaches
我们可以在工作流程中执行，
that we can implement in our workflow,
他们彼此独立独立
and they're all independent interdependent from one another.
所以，嗯，我们， 使用激光切割本周，这是
So, um, we, the use of laser cut this week, this is
能够创造模块模式的是什么？
what will make possible to create modular patterns without,
嗯，任何浪费或至少
uh, any waste or at least
尽可能减少浪费。
to minimize the waste as much as possible.
呃，我们，我们将，呃， 不使用任何缝合，任何缝合。
Uh, we, we'll, uh, not use any stitches, any seams.
所以我们要制作无缝的服装
So we'll produce seamless garments
没有缝纫机，就可以成像
that can be imaged without, um, a sewing machine
可以重新配置 通过，
that can be reconfigurable through,
嗯，通过互锁。
um, through interlocking.
就像是用软材料制作的乐高砖
So like a puzzle like Lego brick that made of soft materials
这样系统的每一块都可以被采纳，
so that every piece in the system can be adopted,
也可以升级，修复，呃，替换，呃，
can be also upgraded, repaired, uh, replaced, uh,
不需要更换旧衣服
without the need of replacing the old garment
或者买个新的
or just buying a new one.
呃，当你谈到 数字制造，
Uh, when you talk also about digital fabrication,
我们讨论的是本地生产的开放式设计
we talk about open design for local production.
所以这个设计可以在全世界共享
So a design that can be shared all over the world
以及不同的人可以做出贡献的地方。
and where different people can contribute.
一个设计可以，可以重新混合 在，呃，
A design can, can be remixed in, uh,
人类在海外的位置，
human location overseas,
也可以按要求定制
and that can be customized also on demand so
你不需要任何实物库存。
that you don't need any physical stock.
所以所有这些方法一起 真正的贡献
So all these approaches together really contribute
使时尚更适应性更强，更方便使用，
to make fashion more adaptable, accessible,
更可持续
and more sustainable.
这是偷看工作流程
This is a sneak peek at the workflow of
这周你会做什么？
what you will be doing this week.
这是最早的例子之一
It's one of the earliest example
这是 Fabricademy 的一个校友案例。[人名识别不清]
that we have in Fabric Academy by an aluminum set.
我是杰西卡史丹利 我想说的是
I'm Jessica Stanley, and, uh, what I want to say here is
这一点对研究模块也很重要，
that this important also to look at the module,
还要超越旧制度
but also to look beyond it at the old system
每一个作品，嗯，不知何故， 一个意义可以融合，
where every piece, um, somehow a meaning can integrate,
可以融入，可以互锁，也可以进化.
can fit in, can interlock, and can evolve.
呃，这周你会自己来
Uh, this then this week you'll be coming up your own
模块与您的想法。
module with your idea.
我们将通过两个矢量文件，呃，设计，数字化
We will digitalize it through a two vector file, uh, design
或者三维模型软件
or, uh, 3D modeling software.
我们用激光切割 就像你在照片里看到的
We'll laser cut, um, like you can see here in the picture,
确保没有浪费，没有残骸，
ensuring there is no waste, no scraps left,
我们会以多种可能的方式集结
and we'll assemble in many possible ways.
我们来看看一些项目
So let's have a look now at some projects
在 Fabricademy 中开发的作品，
that have been developed in fabric that also, uh,
之前在外边
were out there before
因为这个概念
because the concept
穿无缝衣物其实是...
of seamless clothing is actually something, uh,
那是10多年前发生的。
that was there more than 10 years ago.
这是我最喜欢的收藏之一。
This is one of my favorite collection.
这是在2013年做的
It was made in 2013
并首次出现在东京设计周.
and made its first appearance at the Tokyo Design Week.
是克罗地亚设计师做的
Uh, it's made by Croatian designers
并且非常专注于一个方块的模块.
and very much focused on the module of a square.
所以它只是一个模块，呃，激光切割
So it's only one module, uh, laser cut
以各种比例排列，
and to at different scales, able to interlock
和类似的模块创建，呃，这个3D惊人
with similar modules to create, uh, this 3D stunning
和复杂的配置。
and intricate configuration.
和同样的孩子，这是有趣的
And with the same kids, it's interesting
我们不仅能造出一拳 还能造出配件
how we can build not just a punch, but actually accessories
和服装同时。
and garment at the same time.
嗯，所以我简短地谈论了这一点。
Uh, so I talked briefly about that.
因此，这是检察官的集体倡议，一个项目。
So this is the Prosecutor collective initiative, a project
十年前在荷兰
of more than 10 years ago in the Netherlands.
这是第一次在概念中引入，
That was the first time was introduced in the concept of,
开放式设计 模块设计
um, open design, modular design
在MakeSpace的法布实验室时尚
for fashion in a fab lab in MakeSpace.
所以我们可以去生产 和激光切割
So we, uh, we could go to produce and laser cut
或CNCA椅子 第一次。
or CNCA chair for the first time.
呃，制造者，嗯，社区可以进入
Uh, the, the maker, um, community there could have access
到模板 他们准备切 制作你自己，呃，
to templates they were ready to cut for making your own, uh,
织物，不同的材料范围，呃，
fabric, a different range of materials, uh,
以不同的模块前进。
moving forward with different kinds of modules.
我总是很欣赏这份工作
I always appreciate the work.
我的意思是，在日本 由月亮，
I mean, in Japan by zuki,
它是一个单一的模块 克隆过和过相同的大小。
it's a single module cloned over and over the same size.
同样有趣的是，我们可以，我们，
And it is also interesting here that we can, we,
同样的模块，你可以重现，嗯，
the same module, you're able to recreate, um,
各种衣服
different kinds of items of garments
比如说 活生生的茧
and this, for example, living cocoon.
所以，实际上 出自阴道
So something that actually goes out of the silhouette
身体，并扩展成多个方向。
of the body and expand in multiple directions.
说到模块
Uh, speaking about modules
和工具包，这是一个很好的例子 在苏霍，呃，
and kit, this is a nice example by in Soho, uh,
极多边形
very polygonal
和非常几何，嗯，不同的，嗯，
and very geometrical, um, different, um,
大小不同的三角形， 仍然可以
triangles at different sizes, still able
互相交错
to interlock with one another.
我们在这里可以看到一个例子
And we can see here an example
在另一个层面，也定制定制，
of custom customization also at another level,
我们有不同的材料，不同的颜色，
we had different materials, different colors,
不同的纹理 和不同的方式 分布，嗯，
different textures and different ways to distribute the, um,
不同位置的模块。
the modules in different locations of the body.
嗯，我们当然不限于使用，嗯，直线，
Um, we're not of course limited to use, um, straight lines,
多边形，或常规形状.
polygons, or regular shapes.
所以这是同样的，呃，设计，
So this is the same, uh, designing,
但当然是完全不同的方法
but of course a completely different approach.
也在这里，激光切割 用来生产种类
Also here, the laser cut is used to produce kind
一些模块中的装饰穿孔
of a decoration perforation in some modules that is started
基于几何线和多边形
of being, uh, based on, uh, geometric lines and polygons.
呃，你可以看到更多的介绍，呃，
Uh, you can see here more introduction of, uh,
自然元素或更多有机线.
naturalistic elements or more organic lines.
嗯，我们仍在谈论 模块和构造。
Um, we're still speaking about modules and constructions.
呃，呃，我最喜欢的工作，呃，收藏
Uh, uh, favorite of mine is the work, uh, collection
2015年新陈代谢.
of metabolism of 2015.
所以我们还是十年前在日本。
So we're still 10 years ago in Japan.
呃，Ola Ang我根据这个模块做了一个很好的收藏
Uh, Ola Ang I made a great collection based on the module
一个广场，我也邀请
of a square, and I also invite
来看看这个广泛的研究，我的手。
to have a look at this extensive research, my hand.
然后你可以在你可以看到的网站上找到它
Then you can find it on the website where you can see
草图是如何变成这个模块的
how the sketches are turned into this module
这让自己完全关闭 成为3D。
that allows itself to be fully closed and become 3D.
同样的模块允许您创建这种
And the same module allows you to create this kind
夹克，还有裙子
of reconfigurable, um, jacket, but also skirt
还有一个袋子，都说
and a bag, all according
受到六十年代日本运动的启发
and inspired by this Japanese movement of the sixties,
关于可配置的建筑
about the configurable architecture were
初步整合。
initial integration.
但当然，你并不有限
But of course, you're not limited
应用这种常态技术，呃，时尚。
to apply this constant technique, uh, fashion.
例如，我们也可以谈论家具。
We can also talk about furniture, for example.
记住这张照片在右边，
Keep in mind this picture on the right,
因为我回到了它，呃， 在几个幻灯片。
because I went back to it, uh, in a couple of slides.
呃，所以这是有趣的
Uh, so it's interesting
如何在此发展这种平面图案
how here you can also develop this kind of flat patterns
可以让你在房子里盖家具
that can be allow you to cover, uh, furniture in the house
像VA，呃，物体，沙发，
like VAs, uh, objects, couches,
椅子 当然还有地毯
chairs, and of course carpet.
所以想象一个地毯，可以生长 在任何大小
So imagine a carpet that can grow in any size according
房间的大小 也欢迎，呃，
to the size of the room that also welcomes, uh,
不同的质量元素，可以在任何时刻成为3D.
different quality elements that can become 3D at any point.
或者另一个好的例子是，例如，袋，
Or another good example is, for example, bags,
篮子收藏.
basket collections.
我真的很感谢奥斯卡·马斯卡拉的工作
I really appreciate the work of Oscar mascara
这是用一种皮革废料。
and this is using a sort of leather scraps.
通过开放式设计 数字设计也不错
So it's also nice how through open design, digital design
和捏造，我们也可以使用
and fabrication, we can also make use
重新思考，嗯，传统。
and rethink, um, traditional.
接下来，这个例子，嗯，它得到了灵感
So next, this example, um, it was getting inspired
通过编织，我们可以调整设计 创建这种
by weaving and we can adjust design for creating these kind
不需要其他辅助材料的模块
of modules that don't need other supportive material
并创建类型
to interlock and create kind
电池关闭篮子和容器。
of cell closing baskets and containers.
同样的包装概念，
And on the same concept of packaging,
我一直很欣赏Km的工作
I always appreciate the work of km.
这也是2019年的胜负或红字之一.
That was also the win or one of the red of the word in 2019.
我认为这是一个非常聪明的主意。
This is a very clever idea, I believe.
嗯，这种可重复使用的包装 制造
Um, this kind of reusable packaging that is made
基本上装任何物品。
to fit any item basically.
从瓶子到书 一直到杂货店
So from the bottle to the book, um, all the way to grocery,
它是一个单一的模块 以简单的方式相互连接。
it is one single module that interlocks in an easy way.
你可以看到这里在幻灯片上， 像善良的
And you can see here on top of the slide, like kind
细节，呃，适合任何物品，
of a detail, uh, to fit any item,
嗯，对决议。
um, to the resolution.
嗯，激光切割，让我们说，
Um, the laser cut, let's say,
以及我们能够合作的精确度，
and the precision that we can work with,
但同时也是矢量文件。
but also the vector file.
当然也可以在很小的地方工作
Were of course able to also work at the very tiny, uh,
就像珠宝一样
scale, like in the case of jewelry.
这也是，呃，不同的剩菜
This were also, uh, different leftovers
各种材料。
of different materials.
在尼太兰也有接近
Um, is approached also in the Netherland
大约五年前， 发射这种
around five years ago that launched this kind
包括帽子、手镯等饰品
of collection featuring accessories like hats, bracelet,
耳环和可以定制的项链
earrings, and necklace that you can customize
带有任何物质颜色
with any material color
让他们在不同的地方生长。
and let them grow in different locations.
呃，我们现在移动 看什么社区
Uh, we're moving now to see what the Community
以及 Fabricademy 在过去这些年制作的作品，不仅是
and Fabric academy, uh, made in these past years, not just
在世俗时尚周
during the secular fashion week,
但实际上在讲习班上。
but actually during workshops.
嗯，活动靴子来了。
Uh, event boot come.
我总是喜欢从这个项目开始
And I always like to begin, uh, with this project.
我真的很感激事实的纺织品
I really appreciate fact textiles
还有哥斯达黎加的维里塔斯大学
and, um, university Veritas in Costa Rica.
这是一个越来越大的点 节目有，呃，相当复杂，
It's a growing point show there is, uh, quite intricate,
但实际上是一个模块 重复
but is actually made of a single module that is repeated
复制一个模块
and cloned over and over a module of composed
两圈之间，犹如铁链相连，
of two circles, like a chain that are joined together,
其中，呃，一个作为开场
which, uh, where one as an opening
一个是像链子一样进屋的完整形状
and one as a full shape that goes inside like a chain.
我们可以谈谈传统
Um, we can talk about, um, traditions.
阿拉伯语图案也是共同来源
Arabic patterns are also a common source
在公立学校的灵感。
of inspiration in public academy.
我很感激 两个版本
I appreciate, uh, the two versions.
呃，它们是基于同一个模块 三角在这里
Uh, they're based on the same module of a triangle here
在完全不同的地点制作
and made in completely different locations
两个不同的学生。
by two different students.
所以，在第一种情况下，我们有一个地址 是创建的
So in the first case, we have a address that was created
后面有这种装饰
with this kind of, uh, decoration on the back.
第二种选择是，嗯，基本上是实质性的
And the second option is, uh, basically material
和，呃，我们剪 生产这些长袖。
and, uh, mod that we cut to produce these long sleeves.
Fabricademy 中有很多包袋的案例。
Uh, we have a lot of example of bags in fabric academy.
所以，嗯，用同样的2D模型， 我们实际上能够
So, um, with the same 2D models, we are actually able
在 3D 中转换为某种
to convert them in something 3D to something
这完全关闭。
that fully closes.
呃，我们在这里谈论，呃，凸连接件
Uh, we're talking here about, uh, male
和凹连接件关系
and female connections.
我们有两个虫子的例子 一个用模具做的 呃
We have two example of bugs, one made in mold, uh,
3年前和去年的一年，呃， 在FBLA巴塞罗那。
three years ago and one of last year, uh, in FBLA Barcelona.
你可以看到，例如，
You can see how, for example,
同样的模型实际上可以用来提供
the same model can actually be used to provide
和手柄一样的补充材料
s additional material like the handle.
或者，在第二种情况下，你可以增加绳子 对，嗯，
Or in the second case you can add the rope towards, um,
包括设计中的多种材料。
including multiple materials in the design.
嗯，这是我刚才在展示时提到的幻灯片
Um, this is the slide I was referring earlier when showing
家具上的应用程序，你可以看到
the application on furniture So you can look at
这里，模块。
here, the modules.
一者为前，一者为后.
One is the front, the one is the back.
有时背部也可以是前部.
Sometimes the back can also be the front.
所以我们有相同的模块。
So we have the same modules.
这是凹连接件的结合
It's a combination of female part
在单一模块中带有凸连接件部分
with male parts in a single module
关闭了一遍又一遍。
that is closed over and over.
这个模块变成了3D
Um, this modules become 3D
在模块的不同位置带来紧张。
by bringing tensions in different location of the module.
比如，这里，当你看到这个，这些很多
For example, here when you can see this, these lots
将材料堆在一起
where material is stacked on top of each other.
在一些你穿孔的地方
And in some cases where you have this kind of perforation
用激光切割器，你也可以，嗯，ing
with the laser cutter, you can also, um, ing
因为你总是可以，嗯，
because you can always, uh,
添加绳索、线索等额外材料。
add additional material like rope, um, uh, threads.
这样你就能带来额外的紧张
So you can bring extra tension
您可以让此配置被拉动
and you can let this configuration to be pulled
来创造可以完全关闭的东西
to create something that can actually close completely.
这就是一个袋子。
And this is the case of a bag.
所以这是非常相似的构造.
So it's a very similar construction.
嗯，你知道这个球体是如何制造的， 所以它是善良的
Uh, you know how this sphere is made, so it's kind
一个不同的，呃，五边形在一起。
of a different, uh, pentagons together.
这是这个新打印袋的底部，粉红色底部
And this is the base, the pinkish base of this new print bag
这是激光切割。
that is laser cut.
我觉得这个项目很聪明
And I think that this project is very clever
因为为了把关节藏在这里
because in order to hide the interlocking joints here, uh,
我的Maona也融入了这些，嗯，
m mine maona was uh, able to also integrate these more, um,
受维尔花启发的异端物体
istic objects inspired by the ville flower
并卡在连接顶端， 嗯，这种基础
and stuck on top of the connection, um, this kind of basis
朝向，所以让包，嗯，更个性化，
towards, so make the bag, um, more personalized,
更吸引人，更接近球队
more catchy, more towards the team.
分层也是技术之一
Uh, layering is also one of the technique, uh,
我们谈论无缝模型，无缝服装时使用.
used when we talk about seamless models, seamless garments.
我们有很多种小马
We have many options of kind of poncho kind
Fabricademy 中的颜色组合，使用凸连接件
of colors in fabric academy, uh, using the male
和凹连接件关系
and female connections.
在蒙特利尔 正在创造这种
And in Montreal was creating this kind
使用一个模块
of feather feather poncho using one module
和不同的条纹， 仿佛它是，
and different stripes, like if it was,
如果它们相互交织，呃，在彼此内部。
if they were interwoven, uh, within each other.
因此，有行 交替模块
So there are rows of alternated modules
后门是封闭的
that are closed in the back.
其次，这里，呃，
And in the second case here, uh,
恶魔乔丹用类似的想法创造这种颜色
demon Jordan was creating this color with a similar idea
创建联邦小马
of creating a feder poncho
有不同的构造技术。
with a different construction technique.
所以，你可以在这里详细看到， 有2，3，
So you can see here in detail, there are two, three,
和四个实际能够合并的模块
and four modules that are actually able to join together
通过另一个模块，你可以看到隐藏在这里。
through another module that you can see hidden here.
所以有点过头了
So it's kind of across
使他们分道扬镳。
that brings them together onto different rows and columns.
阿米，阿米是一个日语词 代表，呃，切
Ami um, ami is a Japanese word that stands for, uh, cut
和折叠，是一种技术，也可以在您
and fold and is a technique can also be implemented in your
无缝衣服，无缝模型.
seamless clothing, seamless models.
我很感激比安娜在这里的工作。
I appreciate the work of Beana here.
清晰受扎哈迪德建筑的启发.
Clear inspired by architecture by Za Hadid.
这里可以看到草图上模块的细节。
And you can see here detail of the module on the sketch.
因此，只有一个模块 允许连接
So it's solely one module that allows the connection
将在多个地点形成。
to be formed in multiple locations.
有个B是激光切割
That has kind of a b that is laser cut
并同时允许模块的一部分
and allows at the same time, one part the module
以子关闭
to sub close on itself
并带来与其他人的联系。
and bring a connection with the others.
所以它只有一个模块反复重复.
So it's only one module repeated over and over again.
我们谈论Kigami
And we talk about kigami
来谈谈可折叠的结构。
to talk about collapsible structures.
所以，你可能已经看到这个，呃，
So you might have seen this, uh,
在 Fabricademy 的第一天。
during the first day of fabric.
这也是另一种方法 我们可以使用
This is also another approach that we can use
生产零废瓶。
to produce zero waste bottles.
想象一下，如果你有一张材料
Imagine if you have one sheet of material
其实可以变成你的衣服
that can actually become something, uh, like your outfit
已经准备好了
that is ready to wear.
我不知道，如果你能看到 从远处这里的底部
I dunno if you can see from far away here at the bottom
有，呃，数字设计，如何一个系列
there is, uh, the digital design, how a series
像活人一样的线条 依次吞噬了木头上的插头
of lines like the living ingested your plug on wood in order
将被禁绝，
to be banned that are concentric,
其中，这幅画中唯一的浪费其实是一个圆
where the only waste in this drawing is actually a circle in
中间你应该在哪里， 把你的脖子。
the middle where you're supposed to, to put your neck.
呃，还在说Kigami
Uh, still speaking about kigami
并会看到一些例子
and going to see some example
这实际上利用了骑自行车。
that actually make use of upcycling.
我想提一下哈贾农场的工程
Uh, I want to mention the work of giant, uh, haja farm.
受到海浪和海洋的启发
So inspired by waves, by oceans,
擦干净其实是最后的结果
the scrub up was actually, um, the final result
在天鹅绒的三米长的窗帘上
of a big three meters square curtain, uh, in velvet
她手里拿着的
that she had in the hand.
这窗帘被激光切成不同的条纹
Um, so this curtain was laser cut into different stripes
通过一系列削减
and through a series of cuts
并折叠，就像，呃，汽车C解释， 她能够
and fold, like, uh, car C explains, she was able
把它们组合在一起，不用使用
to combine them together without the use
任何其他材料。
of any additional materials.
有趣的是，看这里其实
And what is interesting to look at here is actually
即使模型是激光切割平面，
that even though the models were laser cut flat,
她实际上使用的是背部。
what she actually uses is the back.
这边沿着每一边的厚度。
So this side along the thickness of each of the sides here.
嗯，所以我说话很早， 所以我们都包围
Um, so I was speaking early, so we're all surrounded
被许多垃圾
by a lot of trash
我们有时可以转换成宝藏
that we can convert into treasure sometimes, uh,
在我们的家中， 在实验室，制造空间。
in our home, in the lab, the make spaces.
这是约旦的项目。
And this was the project of here in Jordan.
所以她有很多不同的小作品
So she had a lot of different little pieces
和来自不同材料的废料。
and scraps from different material available.
而且，嗯，这是伟大的 她做了什么。
And, um, it, it was great what she did.
所以，她，呃，地图，
So she, uh, mapped them,
她追踪了其中每一个的方方面面
she traced all the dimension of each of them.
她的激光切割他们，
She laser cut them,
她创造了一个美丽的小屋， 嗯，多彩的胡
and she created this beautiful hut, uh, colorful hu
嗯，关于骑自行车， 一个有趣的项目。
Um, s about cycling, an interesting project.
嗯，这个案子，我们在佛罗伦萨，呃，与菲利普
Um, this case, we are in Florence, uh, with Philippe
当时在学院里
in the academy at that time.
他接触到了大量的工业废物，
And he had access to a lot of industry waste,
喜欢时尚 浪费皮革，呃，加农芬迪。
like fashion waste from leather of, uh, Ganon Fendi.
他创造了这种美丽的人
And he created this beautiful kind
类似蟒蛇的动物
of animal snake resembling the, the python, uh,
把这些形状以镶嵌方式恰好组合在一起，
distilling this kind of, uh, shapes in a perfect way
他们后来申请到靴子上
that they applied later on, um, to the boot.
一起完成这个最终计划
And on the way to this final project together
3D打印，呃，
with 3D printing, Uh,
还是关于骑自行车，嗯，
still about upcycling, uh,
中东还有一个项目
one more project in the Middle East, uh,
有很多一次性的袋子
where there are a lot of disposable bags like single use
袋子和塑料。
bags and plastic.
我在这里感谢纳伊姆的工作， 他改变了这个，
I appreciate here the work of Naim, that he converted this,
嗯，这个垃圾，这个塑料袋 成为儿童的活动，
um, this trash, this plastic bag into an activity for kids,
嗯，有指导方针。
um, with guidelines.
我们按顺序提供
And we provided them in order
创造自己的动物 自己的垫子
to create their own animals, their own mats.
嗯，所以有这种 五种模块，呃，
Uh, so there are these kind of five modules, uh,
彼此间相互交错
that interlock within each other.
同时，他们也创造了这种
And at the same time, they were able to create this kind of,
嗯，多彩的灯 用于他们的卧室。
um, colorful lamps for their bedrooms.
如果你掌握遗传学
If you master any of the, um, genetic
或数学，嗯，设计软件，
or matic, um, design software,
你也可以预先模拟你最后的集合
you can also simulate in advance what your final assembly,
最终配置可以看起来像.
final configuration can look like.
这个工作的例子 也做了些什么
And this example of the work, what has done also, uh,
受到阿拉伯图案的启发
getting inspired by Arabic patterns.
这就是墙上的隔板
So this was a wall partition
并在这里赞赏使用行动，例如，
and appreciate here the use of op, for example,
和激光切割器一起创造， 这种，嗯，
to create together with the laser cutter, this kind of, um,
摩尔体内的穿孔.
perforations in the moles.
这样你就可以允许光在任何时间进入，
So you could allow the light to come in at any point,
嗯，希望看到，嗯，关节。
uh, hoping to see, um, joints.
关节也可以是一种装饰
Uh, joints can also be a sort of decorations.
这里的例子包括:
The example here is research of in
这是一件T恤的很好的例子
and, um, it's a great example of a t-shirt.
所以我们不是说模特儿，
So we are not talking about models,
我们在谈论复制到我们可以看到的更大块。
we're talking about replication to bigger pieces we can see.
现在，嗯，左边那四块
Now here, um, on the left there, the four pieces
这件T恤其实是编成的
that are actually composed this t-shirt that is clear by,
通过编织技术。
by weaving technique.
我很感激你们
And what I appreciate
您也可以查看文档
that you can also check on a documentation
是研究的背后。
is research behind.
所以很多测试都是皮革残疾.
So lot of tests is disability with leather.
所以，你真的必须，嗯，连接工作
So you really have to make, uh, the connection work
那种你手头的材料。
for the kind of material that you have at your hand.
然后我有，呃，产品 我真的想展示，
And then I have, uh, the product I really want to showcase,
这是Sterman的作品。
which is the work of sterman.
这样你就可以有一个标志， 你可以有一个图片，
So you can have a logo, you can have a picture,
你可以，嗯，一个灵感 你可以转换，
you can have, um, an inspiration that you can convert,
嗯，进入一个模块。
uh, into a module.
例如，在月球相继时
And this, for example, where the moon phases
我们同时做装饰
that we're serving at the same time as a decoration,
但实际上是一个凹连接件技术单元
but actually a technical module of female
和与另两年级相交的凸连接件，
and male parts that interlock with the other two grade,
这个顶部是活的顶部 但也有披风
this top living top, but also cape.
我也喜欢看看后面
And I also like to look at the back here
并看到这种Illustrator 回来。
and to see that this kind of illustration comes back.
嗯，有一个项目 方向盘现在相信，我会
Um, there's a project of a steer now believe I will
也还在连接。
also still connecting.
这里有连接
It's connected here. Um,
所以一个学生利用了个人电网
so a student had made use of personal grids
这个项目是最后一个项目的一部分 是，嗯，
and this project was part of a final project was this, um,
由形状激发的无缝袋，
seamless bag inspired by the shape,
甲虫的纹理。
the texture of the beetle.
所以也喜欢的方式，嗯， 他，呃，回去
So also like the way, um, that he was, uh, going back
通过生物mcr，尝试相似 通过像素艺术
through bio mcr, trying to resemble through pixel art
还有 身体的不同位置 颜色
as well, uh, different locations of the body, of the color
试图用碎片来配合
of the animal, and trying to match this, uh, with pieces
它可以隐藏 交叉部分在背面。
that could hide the interlocking parts on the back.
加上这个，你还做了外套
And together with this, you also made, um, jackets
这么说吧，嗯，那些孩子就是谜题
and let's say, um, that are kind of kids that are puzzles.
其实有735块
There are actually 735 pieces
它可以帮助你 做21个不同的片段。
that can help you make 21 different pieces.
你可以看到，嗯，一点点的工作在这里。
And you can see, uh, a little bit the work here.
有三个不同的模型，呃， 有凹连接件部分
There are three different models, uh, that have female parts
有不同的削减
with different cuts
和凸连接件部分 允许你，嗯，嗯，
and male parts that allow you, um, uh,
被困在不同的地方。
to be stuck together in different locations.
我有一个视频，呃，稍后 我们展示这个，
And I have a video, uh, later on that also we showcase this,
嗯，呃，聪明的应用程序 不知怎么的相似
uh, uh, clever application that somehow was resembles
在3D mdo 一个动物皮肤。
in 3D mdo one animal skin.
我也感谢你们的工作
I also appreciate the work
几年前在新蒙特利尔的薇薇安
of Vivian in New Montreal a couple of years ago.
所以用网格来制造模块化的吸烟.
So using a grid to create a modular smoking.
我们如何重塑，如何操纵织物
So how we can reshape, how we can manipulate the fabric
加上数字设计和皮革切片。
together with the digital design and the leather cut.
想象一下，如果不是买十套不同的衣服
So imagine if instead of buying 10 different outfits
和不同的衣服， 所以你可以只是创建自己的，呃，
and different dress, so you can just create your own, uh,
每次都变异
variation every time.
我认为，这是一个非常聪明的想法 分享
And I think that this is a very clever idea to share
你有一个基础
what you have a base
和不同的穿孔 本案持有方块。
with a different perforations in this case holds squares.
你有一个不同形状的包 可以插入
And you have a kit of different shapes that can be inserted
给予区别
to bring distinction
或让织物折叠
or to let the fabric fold
以不同的方式设计。
in different designs in different way.
有个学生也工作过 一个类似的概念
Had a student also work, uh, a similar concept,
但更倾向于，嗯，
but more towards, um,
我们能称为模组遗产
what we can call mod uh, modular heritage.
这真是...
Mm-hmm. Um, this is very,
这是一个伟大的项目 关于巴勒斯坦刺绣
it is a great project about Palestinian embroidery
以及如何重新设计这些动机
and how we can redesign these motives
传统教育
that have been taught only traditionally
这么长时间， 并把它们同时，呃，
for such a long time and made them at the same time, uh,
较年轻的社区更容易接触。
more accessible to the younger community.
因此，这是一个项目，呃，以类似的方式
So it is a project that, uh, in a similar way
之前的项目是很多
of the previous, uh, project as a lot
准备是黑背心
of preparation is black vest.
你有一套不同的小模块
And you have a kit of different small modules
可以插入到网格中以创建，嗯，
that can be insert in grid to create, um,
很多动机
many kinds of motives.
所以我，我想说，嗯， 这个项目还有一种，
So I, I'd say this, um, this project also has a sort of a,
教育价值。
of a value in terms of education.
所以孩子们在学习的同时
So the kids were at the same time learning
关于他们失去的遗产。
about their lost heritage.
还有另一个项目成为了最后的项目
And there is another one that became a final project
是Allic的作品，
is the work of Allic.
嗯，其实，嗯， 谈论阿拉的故事。
Um, is actually, um, talks about the story of Allah.
阿拉是，这个项目谈论种族灭绝
Allah was, and this project talks about the genocide
发生在证监会卡西安的人身上
that happened at the SEC Cassian people.
它们是许多年前俄罗斯的穆斯林博物馆的一部分.
They were the Muslim museum part of Russia many years ago.
我欣赏阿拉的奋斗
And I appreciate here how Allah have been struggling
寻找专利动机的文件。
to find documentation of motives of patents.
嗯，他们曾经出席 他们的服装，
Um, they used to be present on their costumes,
如你所见
as you can see in the picture.
而且，嗯，她数字化 在我们的经验
And, um, she digitalized during our experience
Fabricademy 中这些基本图案，
of fabric academy, these basic motives,
他们把她和所有根系连在一起
and they were reconnecting her with all roots.
现在有一部分 这个服装设计，呃，
And there are now part of this costume designs, uh,
用于表演的袖子。
of these sleeves that were used for performances.
同样的软件，同样的设计，
Um, same software, same designs,
但是相反的制造技术。
but opposite fabrication technologies.
我们一直看到一些减法的例子
We have been seeing some example about subtractive
例如激光切割机这样的制造技术。
fabrication technology like Lisa Cutter.
现在我们可以看到一个例子
And we can see now an example
用于打印。
of application to, to keep printing.
所以添加剂制造。
So additive manufacturing.
这是布里奇特公司的工作
And this is the work of Bridget Co.
嗯，他们的品牌可变sims， 谁是一个
Um, their brand of variable sims, who was one
在公立学校的第一批学生。
of the first students that we had in public academy.
所以这里很有趣，你怎么用同一个文件
So it's interesting here how you can use the same file
我们本周可以制作
that we can produce this week
而且，呃，能够
and, uh, able
同时在计算网格中生成，
to produce in the computational wick at the same time,
你自己的TPU织物。
your own TPU fabric.
所以，也可以有弹性的东西
So something that also can be elastic
并表现得像纺织。
and behave like a textile.
同时，一个模块化，呃，工具包
And at the same time a modular, uh, kit
创建自己的收藏。
to create your own collection.
嗯，TPU当然也有 床单，所以它是东西
Uh, TPU of course also comes in sheets, so it's something
让你可以得到你的手
that you can get at your hand
如果你对这样的事情感兴趣的话 你可以用激光切割
and you can laser cut if you're interested in this kind of,
嗯，配置是相当坚硬的材料
uh, configuration is a material that is quite stiff
所以它会留在原地
so it stays in place.
不如布料弯曲
It's less bendable than fabric
它的厚度也不同
and it comes also in different thicknesses.
这就是名为RAF Colada的作品。
So this is the work called RAF colada.
我们今年在瘟疫中做了个不错的活动
And we had a nice activity this year in plague, uh,
在 Fabricademy 会议上。
at the fabric conference.
你也可以看见，
And you can see also,
我也许可以认出来了 现在有一个Kigami签名
I can maybe recognize now there is a kigami signed
或有一个连接，嗯，这是
or there is a connection, um, that is made
通过此箭头可以让模型相互连接
through this arrow that allows the models to interlock
在这个，呃，嗯， 在这部分模块，
in this, uh, um, in this part of the module,
当然，嗯，你可以关闭循环，嗯，
Of course, um, you can close the loop, uh,
您可以应用相同的技术，使用相同的矢量文件
you can apply the same techniques, use the same vector file
举个例子，你自己的材料。
and uh, on your own material for example.
所以，我们要接近一些人相信 这是周
So we're gonna approach some believe it's week
7个用你的材料
seven by your materials.
所以你也可以考虑应用，呃，
So you can also think of applying, uh,
这周你要制作什么
what you're gonna produce this week, uh,
对自己的材料，
to your own materials,
不论它们是基于堵塞还是胶原。
whether they are a gag based or gelatin base.
所以在他们生命的尽头
So at the end, uh, of their life,
如果它们合起来，它们可以被丢弃。
if they com they compose it, they, um, can be discarded.
如果有损坏， 你总是可以修复它们为新的
If there are damaged, you can always recoup them into a new
片材，并制作新的系统、服装和模块。
sheet and fabricate new system, new outfits, new models.
当然，同样的事情 也是，嗯，
And of course the same thing is also true for, um,
这个案子的细菌纤维素
bacteria cellose in the this case.
比如说，我们这里有一个例子 科博查银行
For example, we have a, an example here of a Kobocha bank
最后一个主讲人是一个项目
and uh, last panelist is a project
(原始内容存档于2018-09-26). Eduard de Loreto Bio Q工具.
of Eduard de Loreto Bio Q tools.
所以它也是一个应用，嗯，生物材料，嗯，
So it's also an application, um, bio materials, uh,
从罗斯使用相同的模块
from Ros using the same module
产生不同类型的产出。
to produce different kinds of outputs.
所以生物材料，生物制造的结合
So a combination of biomaterials, bio fabrication
和数字出版物。
and digital publication.
嗯，有一个概念 我显示在早些时候的幻灯片。
Um, there was a concept that I showed earlier in the slides.
镶嵌，也就是 tessellation，基本上指
So the distillation, the selection basically means
这是一个过程，呃， 组合在一起的形状，
it's a process of fitting, uh, shapes together in a combine,
在一个板块中有一个材料，并确保没有空白
in a board a material, and ensuring there is no gaps
或随时重叠。
or overlap at any point.
嗯，这也是我们称之为戏剧性的师
Um, it's also what we call the dramatic division
扎斯，一架飞机在瓦片工作。
of a plane in tile work, Zas.
你从底部看到的两张照片
And the two picture that you see here at the bottom are
实际上是镶嵌的两个典型例子。
actually two perfect examples of the distillation.
当没有间隙时，没有间隙
When there is no gaps, there's no space in between
没有任何重叠，
and there is no overlapping at all in the same way,
比如，三角形总是很好的例子
for example, of course triangles always are perfect example
镶嵌中的规则多边形，
of the distillations, uh, regular polygons,
喜欢等等。
likes and so on.
配方到处都是，在我们周围，在我们体内。
The ations is everywhere, is around us, is inside us.
自然界的例子很多
There are many examples from the natural world,
动物、皮肤中的自然现象
natural phenomenon in the animals of the, in the skin
动物的图案，
of the animals, in the pattern of the animals,
在植物中，在树叶中，
in the plants, in the leaves at,
当然，在微观层面，还有未成年人。
of course at the microscopical level and also on the minors.
如果我们把我们的皮肤 在显微镜的镜头，
If we put our skin on the lens of the microscope,
我们可能会发现一种 荒凉的软体。
we might find kind a desolated oid.
身体小部位也会出现这种情况
And this is also what happens in the small parts of the body
或者，翅膀看着龙的翅膀。
or at the, the wing looking at the wings of a dragon fly.
所以我也用这个，呃，幻灯片 作为提醒，呃，想
So I also use this, uh, slide as a reminder, uh, to think
学科多样性
of the diversity of disciplines
我们在 Fabricademy 中实践的
that we work in fabric academy
我们如何，嗯，从生物学，从数学，
and how we can also, um, take from biology, from the math,
嗯，从设计 和计算 出现了所有
uh, from design and also from computation emerge all
这些方面一起。
these aspects together.
当然，我们也可以谈艺术
Of course, uh, we can also talk about art
从 Escher 开始就能看到镶嵌图案。
where tessellations have been present since Asher was
创作他的马的杰作。
creating his mar masterpieces.
还有几个技巧，呃，生产这种
And there is a couple of tricks, uh, to produce this kind
用自己的图案绘制镶嵌。
of tessellation using your own drawings of patterns.
Escher 使用了一系列数学规则，
So Asher was using a series of, um, mathematical rules
也可以译为对称。
that can be also translated into symmetries.
嗯，我们绝对可以看看明天
And uh, we can definitely look at the tomorrow
以同样方式进行教学。
during the tutorial in the same way.
在阿拉伯世界 在中东 西班牙
Um, in the Arab world, in the Middle East, in Spain
或你身处世界的任何地方 也许你有
or wherever you are in the world, maybe you have traces of
伊斯兰模式 阿拉伯模式
Islamic patterns, Arabic patterns,
这些都是绝对伟大的
and these are all definitely great
镶嵌的例子。
example of the installations.
你绝对能用任何
Something that you can definitely recreate with any
3D模型软件，嗯，搅拌机，
of the 3D modeling software, um, blender,
Fusion，RH或软件.
fusion, RH or software.
现在来看看图案
Let's have a look now at the patterns.
后面会发生什么，他们怎么才能真正联系起来？
So what happens behind, how can they really connect?
所以，嗯，我喜欢开始简单
So, um, I like to start simple
并开始识别，定义两个，嗯，
and start identify, define two, um,
两种不同的图案，你在这里看到的图片。
two different patterns as you see here in the picture.
从凹连接件开始
And start from the female.
这样我们就可以看看，呃，两个部分 聚集在一起。
So we can look at those, uh, two parts that get together
他们屏蔽 因为你最终应该能够拉
and they block because in the end you should able to pull
应该放进去，不应该组装
and they should be put, they shouldn't be assembled.
所以，呃，让我们来看看 凹连接件。
So, uh, let's have a look at the female.
我们可以拿一个圆圈作为参考
Uh, we can take a, a circle as a reference here
看见一个凹连接件物体，像什么东西
and see a female object, like something
有剪线，东西
that has cutting lines, something
一旦激光切开，就会打开
that will open once laser cut
或插槽，东西 开口，呃，一些材料
or slots, something with an opening, uh, for some material
被放进去
to, um, be put in.
我喜欢看这里的邮件， 像，嗯，分开
And I like to look at the mail here, like, um, apart
有四个不同的，嗯，
with four different, um,
像T骨一样 像箭一样
like t-bones, like arrows.
这就是要折叠的材料
So this is the material that will be folded
类似此图片将插入
like in this picture will be inserted
因为纺织是灵活的东西。
because the textile is something flexible.
所以，你被允许这样做，然后会被释放。
And so you're allowed to do that and then will be released.
这部分，因为它绝对比这批大
And this part, because it is definitely bigger than this lot
你们所知道的，这两个人在一起将被封锁。
that you have, this two together will be blocked.
嗯，如果你准备好了，达到这个水平，
Um, if you're ready, reach this level,
您绝对可以开始运行您的模块
you can definitely start iterating your module
并创造出一个实际上
and create something that is actually a
两者结合
combination of the two together.
所以，我们有两个插槽 一个女舱
So we have two slots for a female module
和两部分的凸连接件。
and two parts for the male.
因此，不生产激光 切割两个完整的床单
So instead of producing a laser cutting two full sheets
凹连接件部分和两张床单
of female parts and two sheets
或凸连接件部分，你绝对可以去
or male parts, you can just definitely go
第三个选项。
for the third option.
所以，你可以使用一个模块，呃，
So you can use one module, uh,
以在此重现同样的情景。
to recreate the same scenario here.
如果你掌握2D图形软件
And if you master any of the 2D graphic software,
您可以提前预览
you can actually preview in advance how
模块可以聚集在一起， 什么样的集合，
the modules can get together, what kind of assembly,
可以创建什么样的配置.
what kind of configuration you can create.
所以，这是相同的两个，呃，圆 你在这里看到
So this is the same two, uh, circle that you saw here
上一张幻灯片中使用的，相同的连接，
that used in the previous slide, the same connection,
凸连接件和凹连接件也在这里
the male and the female that's also here.
所以，嗯，什么变化 只是外形
So, um, what changes is just the outside of the shape
有时会改变他们的系统，他们的情绪，
that sometimes changes their system, their mood,
他们的整个想法或整个应用。
their whole idea or their whole application.
他们的连接方式基本相同.
The way they connect together is basically the same.
这是一个例子，嗯，gons
This is an example, um, gons
当然，你并不仅限于使用两个。
and of course you're not limited to use only two.
我们看到一个将模块叠加在一起的例子
We see an example of stacking modules together
或欢迎不同的形状， 不固定， 更有机。
or welcoming different shapes, not regular, more organic.
所以你们也可以互相加注
So you can also add on top of each other,
还有，嗯，在他们之间。
but also, um, in between them.
在背后你可以创建自己的系统，
On the back you can create your own system,
你可以切除事物， 你可以创造成果，
you can cut out things, you can create fruition,
你可以用激光切割来刻东西
you can engrave things with the laser cut.
这也是一个偷看
And this is also another sneak peek to
这周你要做什么？
what you will be asked to do this week.
所以，嗯，同时上传您的文件 在开源安全
So, um, while uploading your file in open source secure
时尚与图片
fashion together with pictures
展示你美丽的政府，
and showcasing your beautiful government,
您可以添加一些指引 以某种方式
you can actually add a couple of guidelines to somehow
规定如何将棋子连接在一起
prescribe how to battery interlock the pieces together
重建你的计划
to recreate, uh, your project.
你可以在文档上再次找到这个
And you can find this once again on the documentation
杰西卡・斯坦利。
of Jessica Stanley.
我想说的是 空档越多
And what I want to say here is that the more slots,
所以你添加的营销线
so the marketing lines that you add
并且你越可能开药
and the more possibilities you are prescribing
让模特们聚在一起
for the models to get together.
如果这剪断 如果剪断线 如果这些是
And if this cuts, if the cutting line, if these lots are,
嗯，在模型的中心，
uh, in the center of the model,
很可能你最终会得到什么
most likely you're gonna end up with something
看起来像动物
that looks like an animals.
所以你会有很多碎片
So you're gonna have a lot of pieces
层层在彼此之上。
layered on top of each other.
这是我刚才说的视频。
And this is the video I was talking about earlier.
所以这就是ra的项目。
So this is the project of ra.
这是一种外套是做的
It's kind of a jacket that is made
包含三个不同的模块。
of three different modules.
这是，呃，我认为决议，是的，
And this is, uh, I think the resolution, yeah,
锁上这个是为了给出一个想法
it's locked this to give an idea
如何组装和众多
how we can assemble and the many
不同的可能性，我们有。
different possibilities that we have.
所以，我们有这个，呃，凸连接件的部分 被折叠，插入
So we have this, uh, male part that gets folded, insert
里面的路 然后被放出来挡住
of the way inside and then gets released to block the piece.
这样你就可以建立联系
And in this way you can definitely create connections
但是，呃， 3D类型的操纵
but also, uh, 3D sort of manipulations
因为你把紧张带入了不同的
because you're bringing tensions in different
模块的部件。
parts of the module.
那么这周的工作流程是什么？
So what is the workflow of the week?
我们一定要从灵感开始
We'll definitely start with inspiration.
所以有一个想法， 翻译他们，嗯，通过草图，
So having an idea, translating them, um, through sketches,
C纸，然后通过数字化
paper C and then moving on to digitalizing through
到矢量设计或三维建模软件。
to the vector design or 3D modeling software.
你会测试连接
You're gonna test the connection
在用激光打印之前
before, um, printing out on the laser
或者你所有的模特儿 我们要排料
or the way all your models we're gonna nest.
所以，当大家来到 理智，我们将尝试
So, so as everybody comes to the sation, we're gonna try
尽可能减少所有的浪费，
to reduce as much as possible, all the waste,
同时减少机器时间。
reduce also the machine time at the same time.
然后我们终于用激光把它切开并组装起来。
And then we finally laser cut it and assemble it.
我最喜欢的项目之一
And one of the, one of my favorite project,
我想这是苏珊的作品 真正，呃，展示
I think is this one by Susan that really, uh, showcases
利润流程是什么样子的。
what the profit workflow looks like.
呃，我们从这个案子的主意开始 是一个灵感
Uh, we start with the idea in this case was an inspiration
我相信是在寺庙里买的
ticket, I believe, in a temple.
我们开始用非常简单的材料重新创造它们。
And we started recreating them with very simple material.
如果你不能在报纸上做， 你永远不会，嗯，
If you cannot do it on the paper, you will never be, um,
能够用布料做，就像纸真的相信，嗯，
be able to do it on fabric as paper really believe, um,
表现得像纺织。
behave like textile.
所以有趣的是，嗯，看到同样
So it's interesting how, um, to see also
在不同的步骤 如何，嗯，通过 只是圆
at the different steps how, um, through just the circle
和广场 她能够回到想法。
and a square she was able to get back to the idea.
我认为这是一个很好的镶嵌示例。
And this is what I believe is a perfect installation.
因此有一个模块 由凸连接件部分
So there is a module that is made of male part
和允许连接的凹连接件部分
and a female part that allows the connection to happen
模块之间
between the modules
和一切 完全适合在一个广场上。
and everything fits perfectly in a square.
这就是激光切割时的样子
And this is how it looks like when it's laser cutted sort
排队和纵队 被布满了板子
of rows and column and it's been clothed all over the board.
最后一点要说的是
And last thing to mention is
我觉得这很有趣 如何，呃，善良的
that I think it's very interesting how this, uh, kind
地毯的结局
of carpet looks like in the end
因为你也可以在负面部分看到这个
because you can also see in the negative part appearing this
实际使用的十字架
kind of cross that was actually used
成为任务灵感
as inspiration for the assignment.
我也想说
And I also want to say
软件绝对是一个工作流程的问题。
that the software is definitely a matter of workflow.
所以我就用它来对付他们
So I I actually use the for them together.
这周你有很多选择
Sometimes you have many options this week, um,
您已经使用 3D 建模软件
you have been using for now 3D modeling software
当然，矢量设计可以嵌入文件
and of course vector design to nest your file.
所以，嗯，你肯定可以创建自己的工作流程
So, um, you can definitely create your own workflow
或者试试，嗯， 护理模型，例如。
or give it a try, um, to paramedic modeling, for example.
所以，或者，呃， Fusion360或呃，玻璃软件 Rhino
So either, uh, fusion 360 or uh, glass software for Rhino
或者，嗯，一个加注 搅拌机
or, um, one of the add-ons for blender
从头开始
and start doing that from scratch.
从3D建模软件开始的优点是
The advantage of starting with the 3D modeling software is
一旦你拿到文件，你可以工作 比如说，
that once you have the file there, you can work for example,
同时，对于3D打印机 稍后，
at the same time for the 3D printer later on,
或者，呃，你可以做另一个方式
or, uh, you can do the other way around
然后在PNG、SVG和PDF上导入
and import later on the PNG, the the SVG and the PDF
然后开始挤压它们。
and then proceeding to extrude them.
呃，有两件事情是激光切割器，所以
Uh, couple of things were the laser cutter, uh, so
我们要用矢量指数来工作
we're gonna work with vector fi.
所以，呃，非常重要 设置，呃，例如，
So, uh, very important to set the, uh, for example,
矢量的颜色空间
the color space of the vector
设计软件，你会使用。
design software that you'll be using.
任意一个Illustrator
Either Inscape illustrator
或任何其他处理，嗯，
or any other open source software that handles, um,
颜色向量。
colors vectors.
把它们设定为LGB， 创建当然的衣橱循环
So setting them to LGB, creating of course closet loops
让激光卡能够剪掉
for the laser card to be able to cut out
将描边线设为0.1毫米
and set the stroke line to 0.1 millimeter
或者在可能的时候发线。
or hairline when possible.
完美的排料就是这样
This is what a perfect nesting looks like.
这是Stephanie Johnson的作品
This is a project of Stephanie Johnson in
几年前的阿姆斯特丹
Amsterdam couple of years ago.
所以，你可以看到，嗯，激光切割床
So you can see, um, the laser cutting bed
以及所有模块和结果。
with all the modules together and the outcome.
所以，没有缺口， 完全没有倒退。
So no gaps, no relapsing at all.
并须除去双行.
And be sure also to remove the double lines.
呃，我们是在谈论 早些时候，所以
Uh, we are speaking about this earlier, so
当然有很多方法，有很多应用
of course there are many ways, there are many applications
其实，呃，现在照顾 排料。
that actually, uh, nowadays take care of the nesting.
对我们来说 这对CNC机器更有用
For us. This is more useful, um, for the CNC machine,
例如，我们也有不同大小的地方。
for example, where we have also different sizes.
我通常独自排料
I usually do the nesting, uh, by myself
或有一个导管， 但当然欢迎你使用
or there is a catheter, but of course you're welcome to use
并尝试许多软件
and try out many software
可在互联网上查阅。
that are available on the internet.
SVG排料对SSVG很有用
SVG Nest, uh, works very good for SSVG
和矢量文件 以及深到io。
and vector files as well as deepness to io.
最后，嗯，激光剪切文件。
And finally, um, laser cutting file.
嗯，激光切割不会永远。
Um, laser cutting will not take forever.
永远需要的是样本部分
What will take forever is actually the sample part.
所以，嗯，一旦你有你的工具包，
So, um, once you have your kit,
你可以探索不同的配置 不同的方式，
you can explore different configuration, different ways,
还有不同的应用。
different applications also.
这是一个很好的例子 松散的枪。
So this is a very nice example of loose gers.
这是我们用不同形状的药包
This is our kit made of different, um, ware shapes,
所有不同的尺寸 他们可以相互连接，嗯，
all the different sizes they were able to interlock, um,
以不同的方式 创造出...
in different, uh, in different ways, creating also, uh,
三维配置.
3D configurations.
所以，同时，当工具包，你可以
So at the same time when the kit, you are able
以生产彩色的、肩部的、
to produce colored pieces, shoulder pieces,
和各种胡须。
and different kinds of hus.
最后一点关于材料。
And last thing about materials.
所以，当然，嗯，有很多材料是合适的
So of course, um, there are many materials that are suitable
用于激光切割，但也是真实的 材料
for the laser cut, but it's also true that are materials
能够遏制应该禁止的建设和平委员会。
that can contain PBC that should be banned.
任何含 PVC，即聚氯乙烯的材料，
So anything containing PVC that is poly chloride, uh,
因为它会释放氯
can be toxic because it'll release chlorine
激光切断时加气.
gas when laser are cut.
这对机器本身的危害——此处原字幕识别有疑点。
This is not, uh, harmful for the machine itself,
也是为了你的健康和环境
but also for your health and for the environment.
所以永远要确定，嗯， 检测这种
So always be sure, um, to detect the kind
手握着的材料
of material you have at your hand
尝试用厚度工作，呃，
and try to work with a thickness, uh,
1至2毫米之间。
between one or two millimeters.
合成的木头感觉
Uh, synthetic felt wood felt.
嗯，这是绝对好的 用于原型，
Um, it's definitely good to be used for prototyping,
潜水 织物 印刷纤维 绒毛
scuba diving, fabric, print fiber, uh, velvet
还有蔬菜d，真皮当它来的时候
and also vegetable d, genuine leather when it comes
到棉线丹名称。
to cotton linein dan name.
这些材料绝对可以被激光切割
This materials can definitely be laser cut,
但是他们会撕裂的
but they, they will tear bit.
他们不太好
They're not very good
并适合创建互联系统。
and suitable for creating interlocking systems.
你还可以利用，嗯，
You can also make use of, um,
你一直在谈论可持续性升降，
you've been talking about sustainability upcycling,
你也可以开始收集废料
so you can also start collecting fabric waste
还有你所在位置的废品
and scraps you have at your location.
永远要确定你有什么材料
Always be sure of the kind of material that you have,
嗯，在激光切割之前。
uh, before laser cutting.
衣服，呃，生物材料，当然，
The full garment, uh, biomaterials of course,
嗯，也可以用来。
um, can also be used.
不能使用的是含 PVC 的 vinyl 材料。
And what cannot be used is vinyl
含有PBC的材料。
materials containing PBC.
所以泡沫聚酯织物
So foam polyester fabric
以及用网状的织物。
and also fabrics that are made of mesh.
编织而成的不起作用
And the ones that are made in woven, it doesn't really work,
用来制造互联系统
uh, for making interlocking systems.
呃，我不会播放视频，嗯，因为我们迟到了，
Uh, I'll not play the video, um, because we're late,
但你不能总是，呃， 做我们所说的烧伤测试
but you cannot always, uh, do what we call a burn test
为了侦测
in order to detect
并理解你手中的这种材料。
and understand the kind of material you have at your hand.
嗯，有许多教程， 有很多表
Um, there are many tutorials, there are many tables
比较不同材料
that compare different materials
或者你可以做一个简单的把戏 燃烧一点点
or you can just do a simple trick burning a little bit
带打火机的材料边缘
of the edge of a material with a lighter
看看火焰的颜色
and look at the color of the flame that you have.
如果大多数情况下是绿色的，它会包含B，B，C.
If it's green in most of the cases it'll contain B, B, C.
所以，你完全不能失去一个切。
So something that you cannot lose a cut at all.
简言之，总结一下，这就是
And in short, to summarize, so this is
你的任务是什么？
what your assignment would be.
所以请您也用纸张设计原型
So your be asked to design prototype also with paper
剪刀、模块配置、模块
and scissors, your modular configurations, your modules,
你的衣服，或者任何你想要的东西
your garment, or whatever you want in
记住你想做的。
mind that you want to make.
呃，你会被要求记录， 当然工作流程，嗯，
Uh, you'll be asked to document, of course the workflow, um,
参数，不同织物上的测试
the parameter, the tests on the different fabric
和激光切割模块，还有排料
and the laser cutting modules, but also the nesting
在集结之前
before assembling.
因此，它也会被要求上传你的创造
So it'll be asked also to upload your creation
在这个分布式平台，开源，
in this distributed platform, open source,
如此安全时尚。
so secure fashion.com
并提供你最好的特征 与短，嗯，
and provide your best features together with a short, um,
备案 PDF， 您可以在其中设置指南
filing PDF, where you can have guidelines
并指导大家如何更好地组装这些模块。
and prescribe everybody on how to best assemble the pieces.
我认为，呃，你可以得到灵感 从曾经存在
And I think, uh, you can get inspired by what's been there
由所有这些，呃，创造者 学院分享，呃，
by all these, uh, creators for academies that shared, uh,
和我们在一起超过九年
with us for more than nine years.
嗯，嗯，创造，有很多其他项目
Uh, um, the creation, there is a lot of other projects
我们可以，呃，讨论一下。
that we can, uh, discuss about.
而且，呃，你可以找到所有的文件 链接，嗯，
And, uh, you can find all the documentation linked, um,
在这个伟大的平台上。
on this great platform.
所以，我真的期待着
So I really am looking forward
一周后来看你的作品
to seeing your creations in a week.
谢谢
And, uh, thank you.
您还发现应用程序链接到类归档
You also find application linked, uh, the class archive
以及，呃，准则
as well as the, uh, guidelines
重述，呃，任务。
that recap, uh, the assignment.
如果，呃，有问题 你可以，嗯，
And if, uh, there is questions you can also, um,
解密自己或写在聊天。
unmute yourself or write in the chat.
我没有看它。
I was not looking at it.
是啊，所以材料是最重要的东西。
Yeah, so the material is the most important thing.
请检查一下
Please, uh, double check
织物浪费。
fabric waste.
这取决于你在哪里， 你可以把它带到实验室明天。
It depends where you, you can bring it to the lab tomorrow.
我们可以一起看看
We can have a look together.
明天下午三点我们再见面
Uh, tomorrow we will be meeting together again at 3:00 PM
我们的教程是CT
CT for our tutorial.
这样也可以，嗯，开始下载一个软件。
So it can also, um, start downloading a software.
我会把它再次在乳房。
I will put it again on mamos.
我们要做一些 在Fusion 360和，
We're gonna do something in between Fusion 360 and,
和Rhino创建模型。
and Rhino for creating a model.
我们也会使用，嗯，
And we'll be also using, um,
Illustrator 用来排料的
Inscape Illustrator, uh, for nesting.
因此你至少有一个软件选择。
So you have, um, an option at least one
这四个软件。
of those four software.
所以我们把连接放在那里，
So we'll put, be putting the links there,
我们可以下载软件。
we can download the software.
嗯，是的，如果你没有任何问题，
And uh, yeah, if you don't have any questions,
对不起，因为我知道现在有点晚了
I'm very sorry because I know it's a bit late.
获得灵感 看看其他人
So get inspired, look at the others,
那边有什么，看看你的衣橱
what has been there, look at your wardrobe
下周在公开源代码上见
and see you next week with the review on open source,
安全时尚。
secure fashion.